<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cs.CV on Evofutura</title><link>https://evofutura.com/tags/cs.cv/</link><description>Recent content in Cs.CV on Evofutura</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://evofutura.com/tags/cs.cv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>InspecSafe-V1: A Multimodal Benchmark for Safety Assessment in Industrial Inspection Scenarios</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inspecsafe-v1-a-multimodal-benchmark-for-safety-assessment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inspecsafe-v1-a-multimodal-benchmark-for-safety-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21173v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: With the rapid development of industrial intelligence and unmanned inspection, reliable perception and safety assessment for AI systems in complex and dynamic industrial sites has become a key bottleneck for deploying predictive maintenance and autonomous inspection. Most public datasets remain limited by simulated data sources, single-modality sensing, or the absence of fine-grained object-level annotations, which prevents robust scene understanding and multimodal safety reasoning for industrial foundation models. To address these limitations, InspecSafe-V1 is released as the first multimodal benchmark dataset for industrial inspection safety assessment that is collected from routine operations of real inspection robots in real-world environments. InspecSafe-V1 covers five representative industrial scenarios, including tunnels, power facilities, sintering equipment, oil and gas petrochemical plants, and coal conveyor trestles. The dataset is constructed from 41 wheeled and rail-mounted inspection robots operating at 2,239 valid inspection sites, yielding 5,013 inspection instances. For each instance, pixel-level segmentation annotations are provided for key objects in visible-spectrum images. In addition, a semantic scene description and a corresponding safety level label are provided according to practical inspection tasks. Seven synchronized sensing modalities are further included, including infrared video, audio, depth point clouds, radar point clouds, gas measurements, temperature, and humidity, to support multimodal anomaly recognition, cross-modal fusion, and comprehensive safety assessment in industrial environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>