<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Industry on Evofutura</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/tags/industry/</link><description>Recent content in Industry on Evofutura</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:28:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/tags/industry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>In the AI age, 'slow and steady' doesn't really win</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-in-the-ai-age-aeur-slow-and-steadyaeurtm-doesnaeurtmt-really-win/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:28:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-in-the-ai-age-aeur-slow-and-steadyaeurtm-doesnaeurtmt-really-win/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sign up for Semafor Technology: What&amp;rsquo;s next in the new era of tech. Read it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every tech company right now is being judged on the delicate dance between industry transformation and business preservation. This week we got a better read on how CEOs are weighing risk against long-term ambition. Take Microsoft. For the first time ever, it posted a $50 billion quarter in cloud revenue, up $10 billion from a decade ago. But that growth wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough for Wall Street, and yesterday&amp;rsquo;s stock drop wiped out $357 billion in value, its steepest fall since 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple AI Pin Explained: Is This Screenless Wearable Worth Wearing Every Day?</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-apple-ai-pin-explained-is-this-screenless-wearable-worth-we/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:26:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-apple-ai-pin-explained-is-this-screenless-wearable-worth-we/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Apple AI Pin is shaping up to be Apple&amp;rsquo;s boldest rethink of personal computing since the Apple Watch. Instead of another screen, it leans into voice, vision, and context, clipping discreetly to clothing for hands-free interaction. Designed as an iPhone companion rather than a replacement, the Apple AI Pin raises a practical question: does removing the screen make everyday tasks easier, or just more awkward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early details point to a wearable that listens, sees, and responds instantly without pulling a phone from your pocket. Apple AI aims to make interactions feel ambient rather than deliberate. Whether that shift improves daily life depends less on novelty and more on how naturally it fits into real routines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sales tech stack ROI: What C-suite executives must fix now</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-sales-tech-stack-roi-what-c-suite-executives-must-fix-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-sales-tech-stack-roi-what-c-suite-executives-must-fix-now/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sales tech stack ROI: What C-suite executives must fix now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your sales organization is spending an average of $1,200 per rep annually on sales tools, yet 67% of purchased features go unused. According to Gartner, IT spending is growing 9.3% in 2025, but most C-suite teams can&amp;rsquo;t answer a simple question: What revenue did last quarter&amp;rsquo;s tech investment actually generate? Apollo.io explains what C-suite executives should understand about sales tech stack ROI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Recruiting, Retaining Skilled Talent to Challenge Supply Chain Organizations in 2026</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-recruiting-retaining-skilled-talent-to-challenge-supply-cha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-recruiting-retaining-skilled-talent-to-challenge-supply-cha/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recruiting and retaining skilled technology talent has emerged as the single biggest business challenge for 2026, cited by 50% of respondents, up sharply from 34% in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI continues to deliver measurable productivity and performance gains across organizations, but global economic uncertainty and geopolitical risk are reshaping technology investment, hiring, and innovation strategies for 2026, according to the annual Reveal Top Software Development Challenges Survey released by Infragistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Reveal survey shows that AI is clearly delivering productivity gains, but today&amp;rsquo;s economic reality is raising the bar for every technology investment,&amp;rdquo; says Casey Ciniello, Reveal and Slingshot senior product manager, Infragistics. &amp;ldquo;The data signals a decisive shift from experimentation to disciplined execution, as talent shortages, tighter budgets, and global instability force tougher choices about where &amp;ndash; and how fast &amp;ndash; to scale. The organizations that win will be those that focus AI investment on clear, near-term business results.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Use in Breast Cancer Screening Cuts Rate of Later Diagnosis</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-use-in-breast-cancer-screening-cuts-rate-of-later-diagnos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:59:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-use-in-breast-cancer-screening-cuts-rate-of-later-diagnos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The use of artificial intelligence in breast cancer screening reduces the rate of a cancer diagnosis by 12% in subsequent years and leads to a higher rate of early detection, according to the first trial of its kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers said the study was the largest to date looking at AI use in cancer screening. It involved 100,000 women in Sweden who were part of mammography screening and were randomly assigned to either AI-supported screening or to a standard reading by two radiologists between April 2021 and December 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rajeev Surendran Assary on using artificial intelligence to boost scientific and technological discovery</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-rajeev-surendran-assary-on-using-artificial-intelligence-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-rajeev-surendran-assary-on-using-artificial-intelligence-to/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;His work supports battery innovation, critical materials research and other efforts at Argonne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) and computing are becoming increasingly useful as assistants in the search for the next promising ingredient for advanced batteries, next-generation fuels and more. At the U.S. Department of Energy&amp;rsquo;s (DOE) Argonne National Laboratory, these tools are wielded by materials scientists who have spent decades exploring how different materials play a role in the future of energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>India Signals Shift from AI Vision to Sovereign Execution with the launch of IAIRO</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-india-signals-shift-from-ai-vision-to-sovereign-execution-wi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-india-signals-shift-from-ai-vision-to-sovereign-execution-wi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;New Delhi [India], January 30: A decisive shift in India&amp;rsquo;s artificial intelligence journey is in the making with the formal launch of Indian AI Research Organisation (IAIRO), a pioneering institution and a national beacon dedicated to foundational and applied AI research aligned with India&amp;rsquo;s core challenges and priorities. Aimed at catalysing the shift - from strategy formulation to sovereignty and streamlined execution from prototypes and IP to global products - the launch of IAIRO comes at a pivotal moment backed by a position paper titled &amp;lsquo;Sovereign AI for India&amp;rsquo;s Strategic Autonomy&amp;rsquo; by Dr Amit Sheth, the Founding Director of IAIRO.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meta proves AI doubters wrong with $135 billion infrastructure push - Cryptopolitan</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-meta-proves-ai-doubters-wrong-with-135-billion-infrastructu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:47:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-meta-proves-ai-doubters-wrong-with-135-billion-infrastructu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Meta Platforms is pouring massive amounts of money into artificial intelligence, and the bet appears to be paying off through stronger advertising sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social media giant plans to spend up to 135 billion dollars on infrastructure this year. That amount exceeds the total economic output of many smaller countries. The company spent 39 billion dollars in 2024 and 72 billion dollars in 2025 on capital expenses, mostly for data centers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>People Could Be 'Resurrected' in Robotic Bodies One Day, Futurist Believes. Now He's Taken the First Step.</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-people-could-be-resurrected-in-robotic-bodies-one-day-fut/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:41:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-people-could-be-resurrected-in-robotic-bodies-one-day-fut/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The irony is that during my lifetime I thought about digital immortality, about disrupting death as they say in the Valley &amp;hellip; And now I myself have become an experiment in this field &amp;hellip; This is 2025 and I&amp;rsquo;ve been dead for ten years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;dead person&amp;rdquo; speaking these introspective lines is Roman Mazurenko &amp;ndash; or rather, Roman 2.0, an AI persona reconstructed from his posthumous traces. Mazurenko was a charismatic Belarusian engineer who died in a traffic accident in 2015 at age 35. Russian transhumanist Alexey Turchin is now rebuilding him as an open-source, long-memory project designed, in theory, to persist indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NASA's Perseverance Rover Completes First AI-Planned Drive on Mars</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-nasa-s-perseverance-rover-completes-first-ai-planned-drive-o/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-nasa-s-perseverance-rover-completes-first-ai-planned-drive-o/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The team for the six-wheeled scientist used a vision-capable AI to create a safe route over the Red Planet&amp;rsquo;s surface without the input of human route planners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance Mars rover has completed the first drives on another world that were planned by artificial intelligence. Executed on Dec. 8 and 10, and led by the agency&amp;rsquo;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California, the demonstration used generative AI to create waypoints for Perseverance, a complex decision-making task typically performed manually by the mission&amp;rsquo;s human rover planners.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Perseverance Rover's First AI-Driven Mars Trek</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-perseverance-rover-s-first-ai-driven-mars-trek/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-perseverance-rover-s-first-ai-driven-mars-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The team for the six-wheeled scientist used a vision-capable AI to create a safe route over the Red Planet&amp;rsquo;s surface without the input of human route planners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance Mars rover has completed the first drives on another world that were planned by artificial intelligence. Executed on Dec. 8 and 10, and led by the agency&amp;rsquo;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California, the demonstration used generative AI to create waypoints for Perseverance, a complex decision-making task typically performed manually by the mission&amp;rsquo;s human rover planners.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Valuing AI: Extreme Bubble, New Golden Era, or Both</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-valuing-ai-extreme-bubble-new-golden-era-or-both/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-valuing-ai-extreme-bubble-new-golden-era-or-both/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Membership is now required to use this feature. To learn more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View Membership Benefits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At GMO, we have always defined a bubble as a two-standard deviation divergence of the price of any asset class above its long-term real price trend. The U.S. stock market has now been in bubble territory for a prolonged period. Sooner or later, the bubble will burst and the price will return to its historic level.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Beam AI to Showcase Instant AI HVAC Takeoffs at AHR Expo 2026</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-beam-ai-to-showcase-instant-ai-hvac-takeoffs-at-ahr-expo-202/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-beam-ai-to-showcase-instant-ai-hvac-takeoffs-at-ahr-expo-202/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;LAS VEGAS, Jan. 30, 2026 /PRNewswire/ &amp;ndash; Beam AI, a leading AI takeoff and estimating software, has unveiled its breakthrough AI HVAC takeoff software at the AHR Expo. Estimators can now get a full-scope HVAC takeoff in under 10 minutes, cutting hours spent on estimating significantly. In addition, estimators can also obtain bid-ready AI + human-reviewed HVAC takeoffs and Excel-based estimates in 24-48 hours. Expo attendees can catch live software demos at Booth #SU2012 in South Hall at the Las Vegas Convention Centre.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bangladesh Should Deploy Artificial Intelligence to Accelerate Environmental Sustainability Progress</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-bangladesh-should-deploy-artificial-intelligence-to-accelera/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:47:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-bangladesh-should-deploy-artificial-intelligence-to-accelera/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Current discourse predominantly focuses on the detrimental effects of artificial intelligence (AI), with relatively little attention given to its potential advantages. Today, I am introducing a topic where AI and its major fields can play a significant role in our overall lives. The world will face numerous substantial challenges in the future, one of the most pressing of which is achieving sustainability through environmental development. AI can be effectively applied to a wide range of environmental challenges, including climate change, energy management, resource optimization, and disaster management, and thus can play a significant role in achieving sustainability in the future. To achieve sustainability by ensuring a safe environment for human civilization, important branches of AI, such as machine learning, deep learning, computer vision, image processing, neural networks, pattern recognition, data science, and knowledge-based engineering, can play a very effective role in formulating short-term, medium-term, and long-term plans and taking practical initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is This the Robot Equivalent of Walking While Chewing Gum?</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-is-this-the-robot-equivalent-of-walking-while-chewing-gum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:33:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-is-this-the-robot-equivalent-of-walking-while-chewing-gum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Westwood Robotics is proud to announce a major update: THEMIS Gen2.5, the world&amp;rsquo;s first commercial full-size humanoid robot capable of manipulation on the move!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you mention it, the bit at the end where the robot picks up a can while walking? I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a lot of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ Westwood Robotics ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, Helix showed that a single neural network could control a humanoid&amp;rsquo;s upper body from pixels. Today, Helix 02 extends that control to the entire robot &amp;ndash; walking, manipulating, and balancing as one continuous system.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DINE Group: Precision Tools Power Smart Machining</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-dine-group-precision-tools-power-smart-machining/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:14:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-dine-group-precision-tools-power-smart-machining/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Modern manufacturing is like shifting seas, shaped by automation, reshored supply chains and the accelerating rise of smart factories. Most industrial giants steer like cargo ships: powerful, but slow to turn. DINE is a different kind of vessel. Agile, deliberate and horizon-focused, the company has spent the last six decades navigating change rather than resisting it, expanding from cutting tools to complete production ecosystems and, in 2018, into robotics. Now, DINE stands as both a manufacturer and a guide for the global transition to intelligent, connected and sustainable production.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Inside Apple's Quiet Shift: How Anthropic's Claude Powers Cupertino's AI Infrastructure</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-inside-apple-s-quiet-shift-how-anthropic-s-claude-powers-cu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:32:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-inside-apple-s-quiet-shift-how-anthropic-s-claude-powers-cu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s artificial intelligence strategy has taken a significant turn that challenges conventional assumptions about the iPhone maker&amp;rsquo;s technological independence. According to Bloomberg&amp;rsquo;s Mark Gurman, Apple has been running substantial portions of its AI operations on Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s Claude models rather than relying exclusively on its own proprietary systems, a revelation that underscores the complex realities facing even the world&amp;rsquo;s most valuable technology company as it navigates the generative AI revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disclosure, first reported by 9to5Mac, represents a notable departure from Apple&amp;rsquo;s historically insular approach to core technologies. For decades, the company has prided itself on vertical integration &amp;ndash; designing its own silicon, operating systems, and increasingly, the software intelligence that powers user experiences. Yet the demands of large language models and generative AI appear to have prompted a more pragmatic approach, one that acknowledges the technical and resource advantages held by AI-focused companies like Anthropic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Say what's on your mind, and AI can tell what kind of person you are</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-say-what-s-on-your-mind-and-ai-can-tell-what-kind-of-person/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:19:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-say-what-s-on-your-mind-and-ai-can-tell-what-kind-of-person/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you say a few words, generative AI will understand who you are &amp;ndash; maybe even better than your close family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new University of Michigan study found that widely available generative AI models (e.g., ChatGPT, Claude, LLaMa) can predict personality, key behaviors and daily emotions as or even more accurately than those closest to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What this study shows is AI can also help us understand ourselves better, providing insights into what makes us most human, our personalities,&amp;rdquo; said the study&amp;rsquo;s first author Aidan Wright, U-M professor of psychology and psychiatry. &amp;ldquo;Lots of people may find this of interest and useful. People have long been interested in understanding themselves better. Online personality questionnaires, some valid and many of dubious quality, are enormously popular.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Car Insurance Aims to Halve Rates When Using Tesla's FSD - Kelley Blue Book</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-autonomous-car-insurance-aims-to-halve-rates-when-using-tesl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:12:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-autonomous-car-insurance-aims-to-halve-rates-when-using-tesl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The company claims that using this insurance can cut costs in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although earlier generations thought we&amp;rsquo;d have flying cars by now, what&amp;rsquo;s becoming the new goal is self-driving cars. With both autonomous driving and AI on the rise, we should have suspected it&amp;rsquo;d only be a matter of time before the two combined in the insurance landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s where Lemonade, an AI-driven digital insurance company, is aiming to make a mark. The company has introduced a new car insurance concept that is designed for semi-autonomous cars.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>UK government needs to urgently address creator concerns over AI, say two new studies</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-uk-government-needs-to-urgently-address-creator-concerns-ove/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-uk-government-needs-to-urgently-address-creator-concerns-ove/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;PRS and ISM have both published new studies on creator concerns around generative AI, seeking to put pressure on the UK government as ministers prepare to set out their long-awaited plans regarding AI and copyright. The government must ensure creator livelihoods &amp;ldquo;are protected&amp;rdquo;, PRS says&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just under 80% of UK music creators are concerned about AI-generated music competing with human-created music, according to a new survey by collecting society PRS For Music. Meanwhile, in a different study undertaken by ISM, 73% of musicians surveyed said they believe unregulated generative AI threatens their ability to earn a living.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Waymo's London Launch Matters</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-why-waymo-s-london-launch-matters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:39:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-why-waymo-s-london-launch-matters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to In the Loop, TIME&amp;rsquo;s new twice-weekly newsletter about AI. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this in your browser, why not subscribe to have the next one delivered straight to your inbox?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to Know: Waymo crosses the pond&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday night, I went to a press event in London hosted by the Google-owned robotaxi firm Waymo, which announced it was aiming to make driverless taxis available to Londoners by the fourth quarter of 2026.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Who Is Johny Srouji, Apple's Most Important Senior Executive - BW Businessworld</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-who-is-johny-srouji-apple-s-most-important-senior-executive/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:05:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-who-is-johny-srouji-apple-s-most-important-senior-executive/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s future no longer hinges on industrial design or supply-chain mastery. It hinges on silicon. At the centre of that transformation is Johny Srouji, the executive who reshaped Apple&amp;rsquo;s economics, margins, and competitive moat at the nanometre scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 29, 2026, Apple announced the acquisition of Israeli artificial intelligence startup Q.ai for an estimated $1.5-2 billion, making it the company&amp;rsquo;s largest acquisition since Beats in 2014. The announcement arrived just days after Apple reported its latest quarterly earnings, a set of numbers that once again reinforced an uncomfortable truth for the rest of the technology industry: Apple&amp;rsquo;s margins remain structurally resilient, its product economics unusually stable, and its long-term roadmap largely insulated from the turbulence affecting peers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Predicts Infant Development in Low-Resource Areas</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-predicts-infant-development-in-low-resource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-predicts-infant-development-in-low-resource/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking stride towards enhancing early childhood development monitoring in underserved areas, a team of researchers has unveiled a pioneering machine learning model designed to predict developmental delays in infants from birth to six months. This innovative approach, detailed in a recent publication in Pediatric Research, signifies a transformative leap in pediatric healthcare, particularly in low-resource settings where traditional monitoring methods are often impractical or unavailable. By leveraging advanced computational techniques, the study represents a beacon of hope for millions of infants worldwide at risk of falling behind essential developmental milestones.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple buys Q.ai to help devices read our faces</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-apple-buys-q-ai-to-help-devices-read-our-faces/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:54:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-apple-buys-q-ai-to-help-devices-read-our-faces/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;But check your assumptions: this isn&amp;rsquo;t Beats 2.0. There&amp;rsquo;s no new headphone brand to flex. Instead, Apple is paying top dollar for tech that might let your devices understand you without you ever saying a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days we put our phones on silent so they won&amp;rsquo;t disturb us; soon the phone will put us on silent so it can understand us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q.ai has been operating in secrecy since its founding in 2022. Its machine-learning research focuses on interpreting &amp;ldquo;silent speech&amp;rdquo;, detecting imperceptible facial micro-movements, and subtle audio cues to infer what someone means to say.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hybrid SqueezeNet and ML Models Boost Alzheimer's Diagnosis</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-hybrid-squeezenet-and-ml-models-boost-alzheimer-s-diagnosis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-hybrid-squeezenet-and-ml-models-boost-alzheimer-s-diagnosis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent developments in the field of artificial intelligence and medical diagnostics, researchers have successfully championed the hybrid stacking of SqueezeNet features alongside machine learning (ML) models to enhance the accuracy of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease diagnosis. This innovative approach, highlighted in their study, presents a groundbreaking way to leverage advanced neural networks in processing medical imaging and clinical data for more effective diagnosis of one of the most challenging neurodegenerative disorders.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Web Review, Week 2026-05 - ervin</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-web-review-week-2026-05-ervin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:21:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-web-review-week-2026-05-ervin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go for my web review for the week 2026-05.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neocities Is Blocked by Bing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: tech, web, search, microsoft, vendor-lockin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huh? What&amp;rsquo;s going on there? I don&amp;rsquo;t see why they would exclude this domain completely, it makes no sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.neocities.org/blog/2026/01/27/bing-block"&gt;https://blog.neocities.org/blog/2026/01/27/bing-block&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enclosure feedback loop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: tech, ai, machine-learning, gpt, copilot, enclosure, vendor-lockin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting point. As we see the collapse of public forums due to the usage of AI chatbots, we&amp;rsquo;re in fact witnessing a large enclosure movement. And it&amp;rsquo;ll reinforce itself as the vendors are training on the chat sessions. What used to be in public will be hidden.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Systematic Review of Machine Learning Techniques for Predicting Compressive and Flexural Strength of Mortars - Archives of Computational Methods in Engineering</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-a-systematic-review-of-machine-learning-techniques-for-predi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:06:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-a-systematic-review-of-machine-learning-techniques-for-predi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Considering these aspects, a detailed discussion of ML models and their hyperparameter configurations is presented in the following section for the most frequently employed algorithms identified in the reviewed studies &amp;ndash; namely Artificial Neural Networks (ANN), Support Vector Machines (SVM), Random Forests (RF), Adaptive Boosting (AdaBoost), and Gradient/Extreme Gradient Boosting (GB/XGBoost).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present section provides a comprehensive discussion of the most frequently used models for predicting mortar mechanical properties, as summarized in Table 2. This selection reflects the most widely applied and validated machine learning algorithms in the literature for predicting mortar performance. While deep learning (DL) approaches have shown great potential in civil and materials engineering, particularly for image-based tasks like microstructural analysis or crack detection, their methodology differs significantly from conventional ML techniques. DL models, such as convolutional and recurrent neural networks, are designed for high-dimensional, unstructured data, relying on automatic feature extraction rather than predefined input variables. This review focuses on conventional ML methods, which are more applicable to mortar research and allow for easier comparison of performance across studies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abstracting Robot Manipulation Skills via Mixture-of-Experts Diffusion Policies</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-abstracting-robot-manipulation-skills-via-mixture-of-experts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-abstracting-robot-manipulation-skills-via-mixture-of-experts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21251v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Diffusion-based policies have recently shown strong results in robot manipulation, but their extension to multi-task scenarios is hindered by the high cost of scaling model size and demonstrations. We introduce Skill Mixture-of-Experts Policy (SMP), a diffusion-based mixture-of-experts policy that learns a compact orthogonal skill basis and uses sticky routing to compose actions from a small, task-relevant subset of experts at each step. A variational training objective supports this design, and adaptive expert activation at inference yields fast sampling without oversized backbones. We validate SMP in simulation and on a real dual-arm platform with multi-task learning and transfer learning tasks, where SMP achieves higher success rates and markedly lower inference cost than large diffusion baselines. These results indicate a practical path toward scalable, transferable multi-task manipulation: learn reusable skills once, activate only what is needed, and adapt quickly when tasks change.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deep QP Safety Filter: Model-free Learning for Reachability-based Safety Filter</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-deep-qp-safety-filter-model-free-learning-for-reachability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-deep-qp-safety-filter-model-free-learning-for-reachability/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21297v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: We introduce Deep QP Safety Filter, a fully data-driven safety layer for black-box dynamical systems. Our method learns a Quadratic-Program (QP) safety filter without model knowledge by combining Hamilton-Jacobi (HJ) reachability with model-free learning. We construct contraction-based losses for both the safety value and its derivatives, and train two neural networks accordingly. In the exact setting, the learned critic converges to the viscosity solution (and its derivative), even for non-smooth values. Across diverse dynamical systems &amp;ndash; even including a hybrid system &amp;ndash; and multiple RL tasks, Deep QP Safety Filter substantially reduces pre-convergence failures while accelerating learning toward higher returns than strong baselines, offering a principled and practical route to safe, model-free control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multi-Robot Decentralized Collaborative SLAM in Planetary Analogue Environments: Dataset, Challenges, and Lessons Learned</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-multi-robot-decentralized-collaborative-slam-in-planetary-an/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-multi-robot-decentralized-collaborative-slam-in-planetary-an/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21063v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Decentralized collaborative simultaneous localization and mapping (C-SLAM) is essential to enable multirobot missions in unknown environments without relying on preexisting localization and communication infrastructure. This technology is anticipated to play a key role in the exploration of the Moon, Mars, and other planets. In this article, we share insights and lessons learned from C-SLAM experiments involving three robots operating on a Mars analogue terrain and communicating over an ad hoc network. We examine the impact of limited and intermittent communication on C-SLAM performance, as well as the unique localization challenges posed by planetary-like environments. Additionally, we introduce a novel dataset collected during our experiments, which includes real-time peer-to-peer inter-robot throughput and latency measurements. This dataset aims to support future research on communication-constrained, decentralized multirobot operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gemma Scope 2: helping the AI safety community deepen understanding of complex language model behavior</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-16-gemma-scope-2-helping-the-ai-safety-community-deepen-unders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:14:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-16-gemma-scope-2-helping-the-ai-safety-community-deepen-unders/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Open interpretability tools for language models are now available across the entire Gemma 3 family with the release of Gemma Scope 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/gemma-scope-2-helping-the-ai-safety-community-deepen-understanding-of-complex-language-model-behavior/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Improved Gemini audio models for powerful voice experiences</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-12-improved-gemini-audio-models-for-powerful-voice-experiences/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:50:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-12-improved-gemini-audio-models-for-powerful-voice-experiences/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/improved-gemini-audio-models-for-powerful-voice-experiences/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deepening our partnership with the UK AI Security Institute</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-11-deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:06:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-11-deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google DeepMind and UK AI Security Institute (AISI) strengthen collaboration on critical AI safety and security research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Strengthening our partnership with the UK government to support prosperity and security in the AI era</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-10-strengthening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-government-to-supp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-10-strengthening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-government-to-supp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Deepening our partnership with the UK government to support prosperity and security in the AI era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/strengthening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-government-to-support-prosperity-and-security-in-the-ai-era/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>