<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Products on Evofutura</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/tags/products/</link><description>Recent content in Products on Evofutura</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:14:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/tags/products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>RobCo: $100 Million Series C Raised To Scale Physical AI Robotics In U.S. And Europe</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-robco-100-million-series-c-raised-to-scale-physical-ai-rob/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:14:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-robco-100-million-series-c-raised-to-scale-physical-ai-rob/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;RobCo, a Munich-founded physical AI-driven robotics company, has raised $100 million in Series C funding to advance its &amp;ldquo;Physical AI&amp;rdquo; roadmap, expand enterprise deployments, and deepen its presence in the U.S. market. The company, founded in 2020, builds AI-enabled robotic systems designed to operate inside real production environments, targeting industrial use cases where autonomy and adaptability are increasingly critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The round was co-led by Lightspeed Venture Partners and Lingotto Innovation, an investment management company owned by Exor. Additional investors participating include Sequoia Capital, Greenfield Partners, Kindred Capital, Leitmotif, and The Friedkin Group. RobCo positioned the syndicate as a mix of venture investors with experience scaling software-led technology companies and industrial backers with long-term relationships and sector connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dubbing Optimization for Streaming Dialogue and Singing in the AI Era</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-dubbing-optimization-for-streaming-dialogue-and-singing-in-t/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:10:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-dubbing-optimization-for-streaming-dialogue-and-singing-in-t/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI has transformed the technology, the workflow, and arguably the ethics of dubbing dialogue for TV and movies in recent years, with the costly and time-consuming traditional approach of a voice actor, director, and technical crew gathering in a studio for live audio replacement very much a thing of the past. The perception now is that generative AI can easily (and some would say dangerously) produce or replicate virtually any voice, but Dubformer&amp;rsquo;s Anton Dvorkovich and Google&amp;rsquo;s Nick Manoochehri insistthat generating the desired voice and refining it toward emotional precision and perfection remain challenging and as much art as science &amp;ndash; for dialogue and especially for singing &amp;ndash; as he explains in this conversation with DigitalGlue&amp;rsquo;s Philip Grossman and PADEM Media Group&amp;rsquo;s Allan McLennan at Streaming Media 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Bets Big on Free AI Training as Tech Giants Race to Democratize Machine Learning Skills</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-aws-bets-big-on-free-ai-training-as-tech-giants-race-to-demo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:07:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-aws-bets-big-on-free-ai-training-as-tech-giants-race-to-demo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services has launched a comprehensive free training initiative aimed at addressing the growing skills gap in artificial intelligence, offering professionals and organizations a pathway to understanding generative AI without financial barriers. The AWS Generative AI Essentials course represents a strategic move by the cloud computing giant to expand its ecosystem while simultaneously addressing one of the technology industry&amp;rsquo;s most pressing challenges: the shortage of qualified AI practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to TechRepublic, the new course provides foundational knowledge in generative AI technologies, covering everything from basic concepts to practical applications. The initiative comes at a critical juncture when organizations across industries are scrambling to integrate AI capabilities into their operations, yet find themselves constrained by a limited talent pool capable of implementing and managing these sophisticated systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI-Powered, People-Driven, Cox Automotive Showcases Industry-Leading Capabilities and an Unmatched Breadth of Technology at NADA 2026</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-powered-people-driven-cox-automotive-showcases-industry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:03:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-powered-people-driven-cox-automotive-showcases-industry/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cox Automotive will highlight new retail, wholesale, EV and logistics solutions at NADA 2026, reinforcing its role as the industry&amp;rsquo;s largest automotive services and technology provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backed by unmatched data and deep engineering expertise, Cox Automotive will show how integrated, human-centered AI is improving the retail and wholesale experience, improving efficiency, and delivering measurable ROI for dealers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cox Automotive &amp;ldquo;Experience More Stage&amp;rdquo; at NADA will feature Cox Automotive leaders &amp;quot; including President Steve Rowley, Chief Product Officer Marianne Johnson and Chief Strategy Officer Jonathan Smoke &amp;quot; along with special guests Yossi Levi, founder and CEO of Car Dealership Guy; Matt Maher, founder of M7 Innovations; Swami Sivasubramanian, vice president of agentic AI at AWS; and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI helps doctors detect more breast cancer cases in landmark trial</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-helps-doctors-detect-more-breast-cancer-cases-in-landmark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-helps-doctors-detect-more-breast-cancer-cases-in-landmark/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence helps doctors spot more cases of breast cancer when reading routine scans, a world-first trial found on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results suggest countries should roll out programmes taking advantage of AI&amp;rsquo;s scanning power to ease the workload of short-staffed radiologists, the Swedish lead researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well before the release of ChatGPT in 2022 raised global awareness about AI, scientists had been testing out the technology&amp;rsquo;s capacity to read medical scans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Use in Breast Cancer Screening Cuts Rate of Later Diagnosis</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-use-in-breast-cancer-screening-cuts-rate-of-later-diagnos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:59:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-use-in-breast-cancer-screening-cuts-rate-of-later-diagnos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The use of artificial intelligence in breast cancer screening reduces the rate of a cancer diagnosis by 12% in subsequent years and leads to a higher rate of early detection, according to the first trial of its kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers said the study was the largest to date looking at AI use in cancer screening. It involved 100,000 women in Sweden who were part of mammography screening and were randomly assigned to either AI-supported screening or to a standard reading by two radiologists between April 2021 and December 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Scale AI CEO: 'Near infinite demand' for AI that works</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-scale-ai-ceo-aeur-near-infinite-demandaeurtm-for-ai-that-works/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:59:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-scale-ai-ceo-aeur-near-infinite-demandaeurtm-for-ai-that-works/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When people ask questions like &amp;ldquo;are companies getting ROI from their AI implementations?&amp;rdquo; they&amp;rsquo;re stuck in an old conversation — it&amp;rsquo;s not the right measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies know they can&amp;rsquo;t fall behind on automation, regardless of whether they can measure the impact. The question now is: What does it take to implement AI successfully? Is it plug and play? Does it require custom models or more fine-tuning after it&amp;rsquo;s created?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There&amp;rsquo;s probably — I&amp;rsquo;m just going to pick a number — 3,000 to 5,000 people in the world, frankly, who can implement critical workflows that deliver value,&amp;rdquo; Scale AI CEO Jason Droege said at a recent Semafor event.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SDAIA launches national data, AI curriculum</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-sdaia-launches-national-data-ai-curriculum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:58:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-sdaia-launches-national-data-ai-curriculum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;RIYADH: The Saudi Data and Artificial Intelligence Authority has launched the National Cross-Disciplinary Curriculum for University Students in Data and AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides university students with practical fundamentals for understanding data and using AI tools responsibly to support learning, work and decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch took place during the International Conference on Data and AI Capacity Building, the Saudi Press Agency reported on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SDAIA organized the conference, which took place from Jan. 28-29, in academic partnership with King Saud University, knowledge partnership with the Human Capability Development Program, and strategic partnership with Elm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Arival's Global Operator Landscape Reveals Post-Pandemic Growth and Digital Disruption in Travel Experiences - Key Insights for 2026 - Travel And Tour World</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-arival-s-global-operator-landscape-reveals-post-pandemic-gro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-arival-s-global-operator-landscape-reveals-post-pandemic-gro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Asia Pacific region, which had a delayed reopening following the pandemic, is showing the strongest growth, while Europe continues to enjoy solid demand. On the other hand, the U.S. market is facing uncertainty, particularly due to a decline in inbound tourism in 2025, which has caused some concern for future performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Are Online Travel Agencies (OTAs) Impacting the Sector?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant shifts identified in the report is the growth of Online Travel Agencies (OTAs), which now account for 37% of all bookings for tours and activities, up from 33% in 2024. This surge reflects the ongoing importance of OTAs in the digital age and their growing dominance in the travel experiences market.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Guide for Robotic Pets in Dementia Care</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-guide-for-robotic-pets-in-dementia-care/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:49:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-guide-for-robotic-pets-in-dementia-care/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the incorporation of technology into healthcare has taken on transformative dimensions, especially when it comes to enhancing the quality of life for older adults suffering from conditions such as dementia. A groundbreaking study led by researchers including Fernandes, Toohey, and Lashewicz focuses on the utilization of robotic pets within continuing care settings in Canada. This innovative approach aims to address the emotional and psychological needs of elderly individuals, showcasing the potential technologies have in bridging gaps in traditional caregiving.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NASA's Perseverance Rover Completes First AI-Planned Drive on Mars</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-nasa-s-perseverance-rover-completes-first-ai-planned-drive-o/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-nasa-s-perseverance-rover-completes-first-ai-planned-drive-o/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The team for the six-wheeled scientist used a vision-capable AI to create a safe route over the Red Planet&amp;rsquo;s surface without the input of human route planners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance Mars rover has completed the first drives on another world that were planned by artificial intelligence. Executed on Dec. 8 and 10, and led by the agency&amp;rsquo;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California, the demonstration used generative AI to create waypoints for Perseverance, a complex decision-making task typically performed manually by the mission&amp;rsquo;s human rover planners.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple loses more AI researchers to Meta and Google DeepMind By Investing.com</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-more-ai-researchers-to-meta-and-google-deepmind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:25:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-more-ai-researchers-to-meta-and-google-deepmind/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Investing.com &amp;ndash; Apple Inc. has lost at least four more artificial intelligence researchers in recent weeks, Bloomberg reported Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The departing researchers include Yinfei Yang, who left to start a new company, while Haoxuan You and Bailin Wang joined Meta, the report said. You moved to Meta&amp;rsquo;s Superintelligence research division, and Bailin Wang is now working on Meta&amp;rsquo;s recommendations systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access breaking news faster with institutional-grade feeds, immediate stock impact metrics, and analyst response tracking &amp;ndash; get 55% off InvestingPro.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slow-growth Volusia candidates tackle issues at town hall</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-slow-growth-volusia-candidates-tackle-issues-at-town-hall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-slow-growth-volusia-candidates-tackle-issues-at-town-hall/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three Volusia County Council candidates aligned with the slow-growth movement shared similar views at a recent forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidates expressed opposition to large developments, a proposed motocross facility, and potential AI data centers due to water usage concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They criticized the current council&amp;rsquo;s spending, particularly cutting arts funding while pursuing a multi-million-dollar motocross project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEW SMYRNA BEACH - Slow the Growth Volusia, a social-media group, hosted a Jan. 29 forum where the three County Council candidates who participated pretty much agreed on everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Two Trees Management brokers thirteen new leases signed in DUMBO totaling 26,000 s/f</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-two-trees-management-brokers-thirteen-new-leases-signed-in-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:52:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-two-trees-management-brokers-thirteen-new-leases-signed-in-d/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Brooklyn, NY Two Trees Management Co., a family-owned real estate development firm, completed thirteen new office leases in DUMBO, all signed in Q4 of 2025: Edit Church, Mammoth Projects, Apply Stickers, Helium AI, Asinc Systems, Biographer, Starling Architecture, View Source, Index Robotics, Neal Beckstedt Studio, MHI Studio, Peterson Rich, and Revise Robotics. Totaling 26,000 s/f, these leases bring Two Trees&amp;rsquo; annual total to over 200,000 s/f in new deals in DUMBO and over 325,000 s/f across the city, which is more than 50% of the commercial leases in the borough in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is This the Robot Equivalent of Walking While Chewing Gum?</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-is-this-the-robot-equivalent-of-walking-while-chewing-gum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:33:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-is-this-the-robot-equivalent-of-walking-while-chewing-gum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Westwood Robotics is proud to announce a major update: THEMIS Gen2.5, the world&amp;rsquo;s first commercial full-size humanoid robot capable of manipulation on the move!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you mention it, the bit at the end where the robot picks up a can while walking? I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a lot of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ Westwood Robotics ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, Helix showed that a single neural network could control a humanoid&amp;rsquo;s upper body from pixels. Today, Helix 02 extends that control to the entire robot &amp;ndash; walking, manipulating, and balancing as one continuous system.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Inside Apple's Quiet Shift: How Anthropic's Claude Powers Cupertino's AI Infrastructure</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-inside-apple-s-quiet-shift-how-anthropic-s-claude-powers-cu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:32:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-inside-apple-s-quiet-shift-how-anthropic-s-claude-powers-cu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s artificial intelligence strategy has taken a significant turn that challenges conventional assumptions about the iPhone maker&amp;rsquo;s technological independence. According to Bloomberg&amp;rsquo;s Mark Gurman, Apple has been running substantial portions of its AI operations on Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s Claude models rather than relying exclusively on its own proprietary systems, a revelation that underscores the complex realities facing even the world&amp;rsquo;s most valuable technology company as it navigates the generative AI revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disclosure, first reported by 9to5Mac, represents a notable departure from Apple&amp;rsquo;s historically insular approach to core technologies. For decades, the company has prided itself on vertical integration &amp;ndash; designing its own silicon, operating systems, and increasingly, the software intelligence that powers user experiences. Yet the demands of large language models and generative AI appear to have prompted a more pragmatic approach, one that acknowledges the technical and resource advantages held by AI-focused companies like Anthropic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Analyzes Speech to Uncover Personality Traits</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-analyzes-speech-to-uncover-personality-traits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:10:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-ai-analyzes-speech-to-uncover-personality-traits/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Study: Generative AI predicts personality traits based on open-ended narratives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you say a few words, generative AI will understand who you are-maybe even better than your close family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new University of Michigan study found that widely available generative AI models (e.g., ChatGPT, Claude, LLaMa) can predict personality, key behaviors and daily emotions as or even more accurately than those closest to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What this study shows is AI can also help us understand ourselves better, providing insights into what makes us most human, our personalities,&amp;rdquo; said the study&amp;rsquo;s first author Aidan Wright, U-M professor of psychology and psychiatry. &amp;ldquo;Lots of people may find this of interest and useful. People have long been interested in understanding themselves better. Online personality questionnaires, some valid and many of dubious quality, are enormously popular.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unbox Robotics to deploy Series B funds for faster global expansion, new product launches; seeks capex, R&amp;D push in Budget - CNBC TV18</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-unbox-robotics-to-deploy-series-b-funds-for-faster-global-ex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:57:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-unbox-robotics-to-deploy-series-b-funds-for-faster-global-ex/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Warehouse automation startup Unbox Robotics, which builds modular robotic sortation systems powered by swarm intelligence software, plans to use its freshly raised $28 million Series B funding to accelerate deployments in Europe and the US, while also investing in new product launches to deepen customer adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Pramod Ghadge, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Unbox Robotics, said the company&amp;rsquo;s growth is being driven by rising demand from retail, logistics, and e-commerce players looking to improve warehouse productivity and reduce friction in automation rollout.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>INVESTOR ALERT: Investigation of Richtech Robotics Inc. (RR) by Holzer &amp; Holzer, LLC</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-investor-alert-investigation-of-richtech-robotics-inc-rr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-investor-alert-investigation-of-richtech-robotics-inc-rr/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;ATLANTA, Jan. 30, 2026 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) &amp;ndash; Holzer &amp;amp; Holzer, LLC is investigating whether Richtech Robotics Inc. (&amp;ldquo;Richtech&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Company&amp;rdquo;) (NASDAQ: RR) complied with federal securities laws. On January 29, 2026, Hunterbrook Media released a report alleging that &amp;ldquo;no material partnership appears to exist&amp;rdquo; between Richtech Robotics&amp;rsquo; engineering team and Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s AI Co-Innovation Labs. Following this news, the price of the Company&amp;rsquo;s stock dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you purchased Richtech stock and suffered a loss on that investment, you are encouraged to contact Corey Holzer, Esq. at &lt;a href="mailto:cholzer@holzerlaw.com"&gt;cholzer@holzerlaw.com&lt;/a&gt; or Joshua Karr, Esq. at  &lt;a href="mailto:jkarr@holzerlaw.com"&gt;jkarr@holzerlaw.com&lt;/a&gt;, call our toll-free number at (888) 508-6832, or visit our website at &lt;a href="https://www.holzerlaw.com/case/richtech-robotics/"&gt;www.holzerlaw.com/case/richtech-robotics/&lt;/a&gt; to discuss your legal rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can AI help simplify put-away rule configuration in WMS?</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-can-ai-help-simplify-put-away-rule-configuration-in-wms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-can-ai-help-simplify-put-away-rule-configuration-in-wms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Editor&amp;rsquo;s note: Sreekumar Somasundaram is a senior supply chain technical program manager at AWS. This article and its content was created prior to his current position with AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core capabilities of a warehouse management system (WMS) is its put-away engine. A put-away engine allows warehouses to model the business logic that determines where each product should be stored at the time it is received into the warehouse. Every WMS provides the ability to configure put-away rules, and during put-away execution, those rules are evaluated to determine the correct destination bin. When rules do not return a valid result, the system either presents an error or defaults to a fallback bin.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>More Developers Than Ever Believe Generative AI Is Hurting The Game Industry</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-more-developers-than-ever-believe-generative-ai-is-hurting-t/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-more-developers-than-ever-believe-generative-ai-is-hurting-t/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 50% of game developers surveyed by GDC think generative AI is a threat to the video game industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new GDC survey shows that game developers&amp;rsquo; ire toward the use of generative AI in game development is going up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, the organization behind GDC Festival of Gaming releases the State of the Game Industry Report, featuring insights from thousands of developers around the video game industry. For the 2026 State of the Game Industry Report, 2,300 were surveyed for the latest one and were asked about a variety of topics, including generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nvidia, Mercedes Team Up to Bring Robotaxis to Major Cities | eWEEK</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-nvidia-mercedes-team-up-to-bring-robotaxis-to-major-cities/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:35:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-nvidia-mercedes-team-up-to-bring-robotaxis-to-major-cities/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;eWeek content and product recommendations are editorially independent. We may make money when you click on links to our partners. Learn More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia and Mercedes-Benz are positioning themselves to join the growing group of self-driving operators offering robotaxi services in major cities, announcing an acceleration of plans to debut the technology in Mercedes S-Class cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two companies will be joined by Uber, which will provide the app used to book the robotaxis. Alongside other European carmakers and parts suppliers, the three companies have begun coordinating operations and launch strategies to push self-driving adoption across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Machine learning models for predicting treatment outcomes in chronic non-specific back pain patients undergoing lumbar extension traction</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-models-for-predicting-treatment-outcomes-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:04:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-models-for-predicting-treatment-outcomes-in/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are providing an unedited version of this manuscript to give early access to its findings. Before final publication, the manuscript will undergo further editing. Please note there may be errors present which affect the content, and all legal disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservative treatment for chronic non-specific low back pain (CLBP) includes lumbar extension traction (LET) to re-align lumbar lordosis (LL). This study explores the use of machine learning (ML) models to predict post-treatment outcomes in patients with CLBP undergoing LET and how these predictions can support clinical decision-making. We utilized a retrospective database of 431 consecutive patients with uncomplicated CLBP. Post-treatment variables predicted included LL, NRS pain score, and Oswestry Disability Index (ODI). Input model variables included pre-treatment LL, sacral base angle (SBA), ratio of LL/SBA fit type, NRS, ODI, frequency, duration, LET compliance, and demographic variables of age and BMI. Initial variables were analyzed to predict post-treatment outcomes. Three ML models &amp;ndash; Random Forest (RF), XGBoost, and Multilayer Perceptron (MLP) &amp;ndash; were employed to handle both continuous and categorical variables, and performance was evaluated for predictive accuracy. Factors affecting outcomes were identified using Shapley Additive Explanations. Treatment was a multimodal spine rehabilitation program featuring LET applied 3-6 times per week, varied between 4 and 10 weeks, and follow-up was performed at the end of care. Improvements in LL, NRS, and ODI were - 11.5° to - 23.6°, 7.3/10 to 3.3/10, and 33.2% to 10.4%, respectively. Among the ML models, XGBoost demonstrated the highest predictive accuracy for lumbar lordotic angle (R = 0.728) and pain score (R = 0.648), while Random Forest slightly outperformed XGBoost for ODI (0.631 vs. 0.616). MLP performed poorly for ODI predictions (R = 0.201), indicating difficulty in capturing functional disability patterns. SHAP analysis identified fit type, co&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top 7 Email Security Tools for Enterprises in 2026</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-top-7-email-security-tools-for-enterprises-in-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:46:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-top-7-email-security-tools-for-enterprises-in-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Looking to protect your organisation&amp;rsquo;s email ecosystem from evolving threats? Explore the top 7 email security tools for enterprises in 2026 that help detect phishing, block malware, and enforce compliance across inbound and outbound communications. This guide highlights essential features, deployment options, and integration capabilities to strengthen email defence and safeguard enterprise users at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides being one of the most effective modes of commercial communication, email has become the most exploited attack surface for enterprises. High-tech phishing campaigns now use AI-generated, highly contextual content, which is often indistinguishable from legitimate commercial communication. Business Email Compromise (BEC) attacks impersonate real executives, suppliers, and finance teams, while malicious content is increasingly remain hidden in links, QR codes, and cloud file shares. Industry reports indicate that over 80% of phishing emails in 2025 contained AI-generated text, significantly increasing detection challenges. BEC alone causes billions in global financial losses each year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>InspecSafe-V1: A Multimodal Benchmark for Safety Assessment in Industrial Inspection Scenarios</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-inspecsafe-v1-a-multimodal-benchmark-for-safety-assessment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-inspecsafe-v1-a-multimodal-benchmark-for-safety-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21173v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: With the rapid development of industrial intelligence and unmanned inspection, reliable perception and safety assessment for AI systems in complex and dynamic industrial sites has become a key bottleneck for deploying predictive maintenance and autonomous inspection. Most public datasets remain limited by simulated data sources, single-modality sensing, or the absence of fine-grained object-level annotations, which prevents robust scene understanding and multimodal safety reasoning for industrial foundation models. To address these limitations, InspecSafe-V1 is released as the first multimodal benchmark dataset for industrial inspection safety assessment that is collected from routine operations of real inspection robots in real-world environments. InspecSafe-V1 covers five representative industrial scenarios, including tunnels, power facilities, sintering equipment, oil and gas petrochemical plants, and coal conveyor trestles. The dataset is constructed from 41 wheeled and rail-mounted inspection robots operating at 2,239 valid inspection sites, yielding 5,013 inspection instances. For each instance, pixel-level segmentation annotations are provided for key objects in visible-spectrum images. In addition, a semantic scene description and a corresponding safety level label are provided according to practical inspection tasks. Seven synchronized sensing modalities are further included, including infrared video, audio, depth point clouds, radar point clouds, gas measurements, temperature, and humidity, to support multimodal anomaly recognition, cross-modal fusion, and comprehensive safety assessment in industrial environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meta-ROS: A Next-Generation Middleware Architecture for Adaptive and Scalable Robotic Systems</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-meta-ros-a-next-generation-middleware-architecture-for-adap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-meta-ros-a-next-generation-middleware-architecture-for-adap/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21011v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: The field of robotics faces significant challenges related to the complexity and interoperability of existing middleware frameworks, like ROS2, which can be difficult for new developers to adopt. To address these issues, we propose Meta-ROS, a novel middleware solution designed to streamline robotics development by simplifying integration, enhancing performance, and ensuring cross-platform compatibility. Meta-ROS leverages modern communication protocols, such as Zenoh and ZeroMQ, to enable efficient and low-latency communication across diverse hardware platforms, while also supporting various data types like audio, images, and video. We evaluated Meta-ROS&amp;rsquo;s performance through comprehensive testing, comparing it with existing middleware frameworks like ROS1 and ROS2. The results demonstrated that Meta-ROS outperforms ROS2, achieving up to 30% higher throughput, significantly reducing message latency, and optimizing resource usage. Additionally, its robust hardware support and developer-centric design facilitate seamless integration and ease of use, positioning Meta-ROS as an ideal solution for modern, real-time robotics AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quick Heuristic Validation of Edges in Dynamic Roadmap Graphs</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-quick-heuristic-validation-of-edges-in-dynamic-roadmap-graph/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-quick-heuristic-validation-of-edges-in-dynamic-roadmap-graph/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.20968v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: In this paper we tackle the problem of adjusting roadmap graphs for robot motion planning to non-static environments. We introduce the &amp;ldquo;Red-Green-Gray&amp;rdquo; paradigm, a modification of the SPITE method, capable of classifying the validity status of nodes and edges using cheap heuristic checks, allowing fast semi-lazy roadmap updates. Given a roadmap, we use simple computational geometry methods to approximate the swept volumes of robots and perform lazy collision checks, and label a subset of the edges as invalid (red), valid (green), or unknown (gray). We present preliminary experimental results comparing our method to the well-established technique of Leven and Hutchinson, and showing increased accuracy as well as the ability to correctly label edges as invalid while maintaining comparable update runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Track-centric Iterative Learning for Global Trajectory Optimization in Autonomous Racing</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-track-centric-iterative-learning-for-global-trajectory-optim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-track-centric-iterative-learning-for-global-trajectory-optim/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21027v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: This paper presents a global trajectory optimization framework for minimizing lap time in autonomous racing under uncertain vehicle dynamics. Optimizing the trajectory over the full racing horizon is computationally expensive, and tracking such a trajectory in the real world hardly assures global optimality due to uncertain dynamics. Yet, existing work mostly focuses on dynamics learning at the tracking level, without updating the trajectory itself to account for the learned dynamics. To address these challenges, we propose a track-centric approach that directly learns and optimizes the full-horizon trajectory. We first represent trajectories through a track-agnostic parametric space in light of the wavelet transform. This space is then efficiently explored using Bayesian optimization, where the lap time of each candidate is evaluated by running simulations with the learned dynamics. This optimization is embedded in an iterative learning framework, where the optimized trajectory is deployed to collect real-world data for updating the dynamics, progressively refining the trajectory over the iterations. The effectiveness of the proposed framework is validated through simulations and real-world experiments, demonstrating lap time improvement of up to 20.7% over a nominal baseline and consistently outperforming state-of-the-art methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>WheelArm-Sim: A Manipulation and Navigation Combined Multimodal Synthetic Data Generation Simulator for Unified Control in Assistive Robotics</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-wheelarm-sim-a-manipulation-and-navigation-combined-multimo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-30-wheelarm-sim-a-manipulation-and-navigation-combined-multimo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21129v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Wheelchairs and robotic arms enhance independent living by assisting individuals with upper-body and mobility limitations in their activities of daily living (ADLs). Although recent advancements in assistive robotics have focused on Wheelchair-Mounted Robotic Arms (WMRAs) and wheelchairs separately, integrated and unified control of the combination using machine learning models remains largely underexplored. To fill this gap, we introduce the concept of WheelArm, an integrated cyber-physical system (CPS) that combines wheelchair and robotic arm controls. Data collection is the first step toward developing WheelArm models. In this paper, we present WheelArm-Sim, a simulation framework developed in Isaac Sim for synthetic data collection. We evaluate its capability by collecting a manipulation and navigation combined multimodal dataset, comprising 13 tasks, 232 trajectories, and 67,783 samples. To demonstrate the potential of the WheelArm dataset, we implement a baseline model for action prediction in the mustard-picking task. The results illustrate that data collected from WheelArm-Sim is feasible for a data-driven machine learning model for integrated control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>D4RT: Teaching AI to see the world in four dimensions</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-16-d4rt-teaching-ai-to-see-the-world-in-four-dimensions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2026-01-16-d4rt-teaching-ai-to-see-the-world-in-four-dimensions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;D4RT: Unified, efficient 4D reconstruction and tracking up to 300x faster than prior methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/d4rt-teaching-ai-to-see-the-world-in-four-dimensions/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Google's year in review: 8 areas with research breakthroughs in 2025</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-23-google-s-year-in-review-8-areas-with-research-breakthroughs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:01:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-23-google-s-year-in-review-8-areas-with-research-breakthroughs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google 2025 recap: Research breakthroughs of the year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/googles-year-in-review-8-areas-with-research-breakthroughs-in-2025/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deepening our partnership with the UK AI Security Institute</title><link>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-11-deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:06:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tyy130.github.io/evofutura/posts/2025-12-11-deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google DeepMind and UK AI Security Institute (AISI) strengthen collaboration on critical AI safety and security research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>