<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Evofutura</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Evofutura</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://evofutura.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Fugazi answers doom NYC's AI bot</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-fugazi-answers-doom-nyc-s-ai-bot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 22:01:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-fugazi-answers-doom-nyc-s-ai-bot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lying means dying, at least for one falsehood-peddling government AI. A Microsoft-powered chatbot that New York City rolled out to help business owners answer frequently asked questions - but was often wrong - has been silenced as the city grapples with a $12 billion budget shortfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mayor Zohran Mamdani said that, while the cash saved is only a fraction of what is needed to fund the budget, it was emblematic of how the last administration spent taxpayer money.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Humans welcome to observe: This social network is for AI agents only</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-humans-welcome-to-observe-this-social-network-is-for-ai-age/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-humans-welcome-to-observe-this-social-network-is-for-ai-age/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the kind of back-and-forth found on every social network: One user posts about their identity crisis and hundreds of others chime in with messages of support, consolation and profanity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of this post from Thursday, one user invoked Greek philosopher Heraclitus and a 12th century Arab poet to muse on the nature of existence. Another user then chimed in telling the poster to &amp;ldquo;f&amp;mdash; off with your pseudo-intellectual Heraclitus bulls&amp;mdash;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The GPU gap in Indias AI dream - The Tribune</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-gpu-gap-in-indias-ai-dream-the-tribune/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:57:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-gpu-gap-in-indias-ai-dream-the-tribune/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;India has entered its AI awakening, driven by talent, investment and a fast-modernising digital population. But the country&amp;rsquo;s ambitions face an undeniable bottleneck: the near-total reliance on foreign-made Graphics Processing Units (GPUs) and accelerators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;India&amp;rsquo;s AI momentum is real, but it is also fragile. The country seems to be entering a rare convergence of talent, capital and policy intent. AI-first startups are emerging fast, global investors are paying attention and the government is also moving fast on deep-tech infrastructure. As per a paper released by Bessemer, the Indian IT sector is projected to reach $400 billion by 2030, with AI playing a key role in this growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Great AI Reshuffle of 2026: What's Behind the Recent Slump in Software Stocks?</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-great-ai-reshuffle-of-2026-what-s-behind-the-recent-slu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:56:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-great-ai-reshuffle-of-2026-what-s-behind-the-recent-slu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;All information and data in this article is solely for informational purposes. For more information please view the Barchart Disclosure Policy here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The North American Tech-Software iShares ETF (IGV) has hit a rough patch in early 2026. What&amp;rsquo;s the cause? A classic case of expectation meeting reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For two years, the software sector bid up on the promise of artificial intelligence (AI) integration. Now, in the first earnings season of 2026, investors are demanding to see the receipts. The result has been a violent rotation away from general software providers and toward hardware and specialized AI winners.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>On AI and tech, Japan seeks to build momentum with UAE, experts say | The National</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-on-ai-and-tech-japan-seeks-to-build-momentum-with-uae-expe/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:54:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-on-ai-and-tech-japan-seeks-to-build-momentum-with-uae-expe/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;UAE President Sheikh Mohamed&amp;rsquo;s forthcoming visit to Japan will be an important step in enhancing high tech and artificial intelligence co-operation between the two countries, a conference in Washington heard on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amane Kobayashi, a senior researcher at the Institute of Energy Economics in Japan, reflected on the country&amp;rsquo;s aspirations to have more strategic relationships with Gulf countries during a round-table discussion hosted by the Middle East Institute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;This could create very important momentum for Japan,&amp;rdquo; he said, adding that Japan could help &amp;ldquo;serve as a hub&amp;rdquo; to create a more resilient global AI supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Online platforms offer filtering to fight AI slop</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-online-platforms-offer-filtering-to-fight-ai-slop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:54:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-online-platforms-offer-filtering-to-fight-ai-slop/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As &amp;ldquo;AI slop&amp;rdquo; floods the internet, efforts are mounting to stem an online deluge of shoddy images and videos made using increasingly advanced tech tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Easily accessible generative artificial intelligence tools, such as Google&amp;rsquo;s Veo and OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s Sora, enable the creation of realistic imagery using just a few descriptive words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Images of cats painting, celebrities in compromising situations, and cartoon characters endorsing products are among the AI-generated detritus proliferating on social networks and video-sharing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The philosophical puzzle of rational artificial intelligence</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-philosophical-puzzle-of-rational-artificial-intelligence/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:53:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-philosophical-puzzle-of-rational-artificial-intelligence/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Caption: Brian Hedden, a professor in the Department of Linguistics and Philosophy and who holds an MIT Schwarzman College of Computing shared position with the Department of EECS, co-teaches the class with Kaelbling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To what extent can an artificial system be rational?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new MIT course, 6.S044/24.S00 (AI and Rationality), doesn&amp;rsquo;t seek to answer this question. Instead, it challenges students to explore this and other philosophical problems through the lens of AI research. For the next generation of scholars, concepts of rationality and agency could prove integral in AI decision-making, especially when influenced by how humans understand their own cognitive limits and their constrained, subjective views of what is or isn&amp;rsquo;t rational.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I replaced Microsoft Paint with a powerful open-source alternative</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-i-replaced-microsoft-paint-with-a-powerful-open-source-alter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:53:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-i-replaced-microsoft-paint-with-a-powerful-open-source-alter/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nick Lewis is an editor at How-To Geek. He has been using computers for 20 years &amp;mdash; tinkering with everything from the UI to the Windows registry to device firmware. Before How-To Geek, he used Python and C++ as a freelance programmer. In college, Nick made extensive use of Fortran while pursuing a physics degree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick&amp;rsquo;s love of tinkering with computers extends beyond work. He has been running video game servers from home for more than 10 years using Windows, Ubuntu, or Raspberry Pi OS. He also uses Proxmox to self-host a variety of services, including a Jellyfin Media Server, an Airsonic music server, a handful of game servers, NextCloud, and two Windows virtual machines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>California Moves to Mandate AI Verification Standards for Legal Practice as Industry Grapples with Generative Technology Risks</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-california-moves-to-mandate-ai-verification-standards-for-le/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:38:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-california-moves-to-mandate-ai-verification-standards-for-le/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;California&amp;rsquo;s legal profession stands at the precipice of a regulatory transformation as state lawmakers advance legislation that would impose unprecedented verification requirements on attorneys using artificial intelligence tools. The California Senate&amp;rsquo;s passage of a bill on Thursday marks a watershed moment in the ongoing debate over how to balance technological innovation with professional accountability in one of the nation&amp;rsquo;s most influential legal markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Reuters, the legislation would mandate that lawyers verify the accuracy of all materials produced using generative AI systems before submitting them to courts or sharing them with clients. This requirement represents a direct response to a growing number of incidents where AI-generated legal documents have contained fabricated case citations, erroneous legal analysis, and entirely fictitious judicial precedents that have embarrassed practitioners and undermined confidence in the legal system.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>'Survivor 50': How Christian Hubicki Will 'Steal' Mike White's 'Power' With 'Narrative Warfare'</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-survivor-50-how-christian-hubicki-will-steal-mike-white/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:36:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-survivor-50-how-christian-hubicki-will-steal-mike-white/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The robotics professor has no ill will towards The White Lotus creator and their David vs. Goliath costar (White gave both of them cameos in the Emmy-winning HBO drama), but he doesn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;believe in being stupid&amp;rdquo; in this game, he told TV Insider on set in Fiji in June 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, Hubicki reveals how he will use White&amp;rsquo;s strategy against him in the landmark season, the people he wants to work with the most, and how his infant son &amp;ndash; who was just six weeks old when Season 50 started filming &amp;ndash; is his new driving force in the competition.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Generative AI is eating culture. See how close it's getting to disrupting dance | Fox 11 Tri Cities Fox 41 Yakima</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-generative-ai-is-eating-culture-see-how-close-it-s-getting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:36:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-generative-ai-is-eating-culture-see-how-close-it-s-getting/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI is eating culture. See how close it&amp;rsquo;s getting to disrupting dance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dancers say their craft can&amp;rsquo;t be duplicated by AI. Our tests show they&amp;rsquo;re right &amp;ndash; for now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bird singing and dancing, as practiced by the Cahuilla Band of Indians, tell a story about the creation of the world, and how the Cahuilla migrated to their current home in Southern California. Moving the same way your ancestors did, perhaps on the exact same land, makes you feel part of the past, present, and future all at once, said tribal member Emily Clarke. She&amp;rsquo;s done bird dance with her loved ones since she was 7 years old &amp;ndash; an act, she said, not only of spirituality but also of perseverance, since bird dance is among the acts of Native American culture nearly eradicated by colonization and U.S. government policy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>'He Will Bring Some Fresh Air': Mohammed El-Erian on Kevin Warsh</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-he-will-bring-some-fresh-air-mohammed-el-erian-on-kevin-w/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:32:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-he-will-bring-some-fresh-air-mohammed-el-erian-on-kevin-w/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;To gauge how Wall Street was parsing Trump&amp;rsquo;s choice, I reached out to Mohamed El-Erian, a famed economist and a colleague of Warsh&amp;rsquo;s at the Group of 30 who has a large following in the financial sector. El-Erian has argued that current Fed chair Jerome Powell waited too long for economic data to come in before acting, and that the biggest change Warsh may bring is to be a little quicker out of the gate.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Former Google engineer convicted of stealing AI trade secrets in landmark U.S. espionage case - Tech Startups</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-former-google-engineer-convicted-of-stealing-ai-trade-secret/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:31:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-former-google-engineer-convicted-of-stealing-ai-trade-secret/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A federal jury in San Francisco has delivered a verdict that lands at the center of the global AI race, the Department of Justice announced Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, jurors convicted a former Google software engineer of stealing sensitive AI trade secrets, marking the first U.S. conviction tied directly to artificial intelligence-related economic espionage. Prosecutors say the stolen material was meant to benefit the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China, a charge that places the case squarely within rising tensions over who controls the future of advanced computing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Guest article: What CES really told us about robotics in the produce sector</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-guest-article-what-ces-really-told-us-about-robotics-in-the/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:31:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-guest-article-what-ces-really-told-us-about-robotics-in-the/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From left: Vonnie Estes (International Fresh Produce Association), Charlie Andersen (Burro), Tim Bucher (Agtonomy), Ryan Krogh (Deere).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Image courtesy of The Spoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vonnie Estes is vice president of innovation at the International Fresh Produce Association and the host of the Fresh Takes on Tech podcast. The latest eight-episode season focuses on AI&amp;rsquo;s role in reshaping the global food system in a series of conversations with scientists, investors, and agtech leaders.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automatic Data Processing Stock: Quiet Outperformance, Loud Signals From Wall Street</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-automatic-data-processing-stock-quiet-outperformance-loud/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-automatic-data-processing-stock-quiet-outperformance-loud/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Automatic Data Processing has been quietly beating the broader market while dodging the wild swings that define today&amp;rsquo;s tech trade. As fresh earnings, new AI initiatives and steady dividend hikes roll in, investors are asking a sharper question: is ADP still a safe compounder or already priced for perfection?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The market is obsessed with the next big thing in AI, but some of the most compelling stories right now are hiding in plain sight. Automatic Data Processing sits in that sweet spot: a boring-sounding payroll and HR processor that has quietly delivered market?beating returns, resilient cash flows and a dividend machine investors dream about. As of the latest close, ADP&amp;rsquo;s stock has once again signaled why Wall Street still treats it as a high?quality defensive play in an increasingly jittery market.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Diageo plc: How a 250-Year-Old Drinks Giant Is Trying to Reinvent 'Premium' for the AI Decade</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-diageo-plc-how-a-250-year-old-drinks-giant-is-trying-to-rei/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:29:35 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-diageo-plc-how-a-250-year-old-drinks-giant-is-trying-to-rei/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Diageo plc is turning a portfolio of classic spirits into a data?driven, globally scalable premium drinks platform. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it stacks up against Pernod Ricard, Campari, and younger challengers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Quiet Powerhouse Behind Your Bar Cart&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diageo plc is not a product in the narrow sense of a single bottle or brand. It is a global portfolio machine: a tightly orchestrated collection of iconic labels, data systems, route-to-market infrastructure, and marketing playbooks designed to sell premium alcohol in virtually every bar, supermarket, and e-commerce app on earth. When investors talk about Diageo Aktie, they are effectively betting on that underlying product platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The big lessons from Big Tech's big earnings week</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-big-lessons-from-big-tech-s-big-earnings-week/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:28:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-big-lessons-from-big-tech-s-big-earnings-week/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Big Tech earnings week has turned into a recurring drama where the audience already knows the plot. Everyone is spending like they&amp;rsquo;ve seen the future, the checks are getting cartoonish, and investors keep asking the same question in different tones: When does the spending stop looking like faith and start looking like math?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subtext across this week&amp;rsquo;s calls wasn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;AI is important.&amp;rdquo; That&amp;rsquo;s old news. The live wire was return on investment, the kind that shows up in margins and guidance instead of keynote metaphors. The market has gotten better at separating companies that can fund an infrastructure cycle from cash they&amp;rsquo;re already printing from the ones that need the infrastructure cycle to start printing the cash.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dispatch from India: How a low-cost, high-quality consumer model can expand India's AI adoption</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dispatch-from-india-how-a-low-cost-high-quality-consumer-m/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:26:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dispatch-from-india-how-a-low-cost-high-quality-consumer-m/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;PUNE, INDIA &amp;ndash; As India prepares for the AI Impact Summit on February 19 and 20, the Indian government&amp;rsquo;s pitch for wider adoption of artificial intelligence (AI) has centered on the potential for the technology to benefit Indian society. As my colleague Trisha Ray wrote in November, India &amp;ldquo;appears to be taking a people-centered approach, emphasizing use cases that have the greatest scope for positive impact for the widest swath of the population.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>More AI security noise - chatbots going rogue</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-more-ai-security-noise-chatbots-going-rogue/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:26:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-more-ai-security-noise-chatbots-going-rogue/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;People rush to AI bots for their most sensitive tasks these days without security leading the way. The Moltbot frenzy reminds us we just wrote about this recently - the difference between AI security noise and high-impact threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For folks who jumped in early and got the Github project Moltbot to tie their whole userland experience together on their laptop, they just got a rude awakening. An attacker could feed it malicious prompts and it would slurp up emails you gave it access to, and send them off to an attacker - all automatically.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A former Google engineer was found guilty of stealing artificial intelligence secrets.</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-a-former-google-engineer-was-found-guilty-of-stealing-artifi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:23:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-a-former-google-engineer-was-found-guilty-of-stealing-artifi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A federal court in the U.S. announced that former Google software engineer Linwei Ding was found guilty of unlawfully obtaining high-precision artificial intelligence trade secrets and providing them for use by China-based technology companies. The decision is seen as one of the most striking examples in the fight against economic espionage in the rapidly growing AI sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Department of Justice announced that former Google software engineer Linwei Ding was found guilty by a federal jury for stealing trade secrets related to artificial intelligence (AI) technology to benefit Chinese technology companies. This decision marks the first significant conviction in the U.S. for economic espionage related to artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>These quiet forces will reshape used car dealer performance in 2026 - South Africa Today</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-these-quiet-forces-will-reshape-used-car-dealer-performance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:21:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-these-quiet-forces-will-reshape-used-car-dealer-performance/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Behind rising online activity and changing demand patterns lies a behavioural shift that&amp;rsquo;s forcing dealerships to rethink strategy, digital execution, and the role of artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2026, the South African automotive industry won&amp;rsquo;t be reshaped by sudden disruption, but by steady and measurable behavioural change. Local consumers are entering the car-buying journey better informed than before, while dealerships are becoming more digitally capable. Importantly, artificial intelligence is playing a growing role in guiding decisions for both sides of the car-buying coin, making life easier for everyone in the car-buying process.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How South African Enterprises Are Breaking Through AI Infrastructure Barriers With Cross-Border Cloud Architecture</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-how-south-african-enterprises-are-breaking-through-ai-infras/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:19:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-how-south-african-enterprises-are-breaking-through-ai-infras/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;South African businesses seeking to deploy artificial intelligence at scale have long confronted a fundamental challenge: the continent&amp;rsquo;s limited cloud infrastructure creates latency issues and capacity constraints that make enterprise AI deployment prohibitively expensive. Now, a technical breakthrough in cross-region inference routing is enabling organizations in Johannesburg and Cape Town to access cutting-edge AI models with performance metrics that rival deployments in North America and Europe, fundamentally reshaping the economics of AI adoption across the African continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Video Game Company Stocks Fall Sharply Amid Fears Sparked By Google's Project Genie</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-video-game-company-stocks-fall-sharply-amid-fears-sparked-by/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:18:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-video-game-company-stocks-fall-sharply-amid-fears-sparked-by/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As such, shares of various video game companies are falling rapidly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of AI used in the development of video games is a hot topic and is often rebuked by gamers. Nevertheless, the industry still believes that Generative AI is the future of video games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With billions of dollars being invested in this field, Google has been developing an AI model capable of creating playable, immersive 3D worlds from just a few prompts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fintech bytes: Docupace boasts 200,000-hour windfall for PreciseFP and Hubly users in 2025</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-fintech-bytes-docupace-boasts-200000-hour-windfall-for-pre/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:15:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-fintech-bytes-docupace-boasts-200000-hour-windfall-for-pre/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, Contio kicks off its crusade against broken meetings with a world-leading decision platform, while Apex unveils an agentic development kit to set firms up for AI success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During a busy week for the wealth tech space, Docupace unveiled new data showing productivity gains for advisors in 2025, while Contio and Apex made separate AI-based announcements aimed at making life easier for advisory firms and wealth platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company estimates those time savings translate into about $29.7 million in productivity gains tied largely to automating client data collection across more than 400,000 accounts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TechTarget's Outlook on 2026 | TechTarget</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-techtarget-s-outlook-on-2026-techtarget/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:15:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-techtarget-s-outlook-on-2026-techtarget/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Nick Martin, Senior Director of Content Strategy and Member Engagement&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been nearly four years since OpenAI focused the spotlight on artificial intelligence, and there&amp;rsquo;s no sign of interest and investment in AI waning. If anything, IT leaders are under pressure to turn boardroom promises into bottom-line results in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond setting organization-wide AI strategy, IT leaders must manage rapidly evolving cybersecurity threats and ensure their data strategy fuels intelligent systems, all with an eye on what&amp;rsquo;s coming next.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Experts Warn Data Center Backlash Could Slow AI Infrastructure Growth - Decrypt</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-experts-warn-data-center-backlash-could-slow-ai-infrastructu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:14:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-experts-warn-data-center-backlash-could-slow-ai-infrastructu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Authors warn unresolved local opposition could slow or block future AI infrastructure projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI data centers are expanding rapidly across the U.S., but growing local resistance is emerging as a potential roadblock for the infrastructure behind artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new report from nonprofit think tank Brookings warns that disputes over electricity use, water consumption, tax abatements, and environmental impact are increasingly slowing or threatening data center projects. The authors say legally binding community benefit agreements are necessary to prevent local opposition from constraining AI infrastructure growth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Engagement Insights Platform Levellr Raises $2.5M Seed Funding</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-engagement-insights-platform-levellr-raises-2-5m-seed-fundi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:14:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-engagement-insights-platform-levellr-raises-2-5m-seed-fundi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Photo Credit: Levellr&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Engagement-focused AI insights platform Levellr announces a $2.5 million seed round to turn Discord conversations into actionable insight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fanbase development and AI insights platform Levellr has announced raising $2.5 million in seed funding led by Fuel Ventures, alongside a group of tech and gaming-focused investors, including Bing Gordon, Frank Gibeau, Phil Mansell, Simon Hade, Norman Cheuk, Playformant, and Mark Pincus&amp;rsquo; Workplay Ventures. The new capital will be used to further build data infrastructure and expand &amp;ldquo;agentic&amp;rdquo; (read: AI-related) tools designed to proactively reveal insight-based recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Broadcom's AI Chip Business Poised for Massive Revenue Surge, Analysts Say</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-broadcom-s-ai-chip-business-poised-for-massive-revenue-surge/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:12:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-broadcom-s-ai-chip-business-poised-for-massive-revenue-surge/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A major Wall Street firm has issued a bullish upgrade for Broadcom, citing explosive growth projections for the company&amp;rsquo;s custom artificial intelligence chip division. Wolfe Research shifted its rating on the semiconductor giant from &amp;ldquo;Peer Perform&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Outperform,&amp;rdquo; accompanied by a $400 price target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central thesis from Wolfe Research analyst Chris Caso hinges on Broadcom&amp;rsquo;s application-specific integrated circuits (ASICs) designed for AI. The firm projects this segment will generate approximately $44 billion in revenue during 2026. Their outlook becomes even more ambitious for the following year, forecasting a leap to $78.4 billion in 2027 ASIC sales. This anticipated surge is attributed primarily to increased shipments of Tensor Processing Units (TPUs).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Agencies are prioritizing flexibility and cost savings in AI purchases, GSA official says</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-agencies-are-prioritizing-flexibility-and-cost-savings-in-ai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:12:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-agencies-are-prioritizing-flexibility-and-cost-savings-in-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;GSA&amp;rsquo;s acting Assistant Commissioner Lawrence Hale from the General Services Administration said early demand has been focused on AI tools that support everyday work and productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As artificial intelligence becomes more ubiquitous across federal government workflows, agencies are favoring a competitive market approach to buying new tools that help with &amp;ldquo;practical, operational use cases,&amp;rdquo; according to one General Services Administration official.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Agencies are telling us they value choice, flexibility, and significant discounts when adopting AI,&amp;rdquo; Lawrence Hale, the acting assistant commissioner at GSA&amp;rsquo;s Office of Information Technology Category within the Federal Acquisition Service, told Nextgov/FCW.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dow's $1 Billion Restructuring Signals Chemical Industry's Pivot to AI-Driven Operations</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dow-s-1-billion-restructuring-signals-chemical-industry-s-p/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:12:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dow-s-1-billion-restructuring-signals-chemical-industry-s-p/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Dow Inc., one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest chemical manufacturers, announced plans to eliminate approximately 4,500 positions globally as part of a sweeping restructuring initiative that places artificial intelligence and automation at the center of its operational strategy. The move, which represents roughly 12% of the company&amp;rsquo;s workforce, underscores a fundamental transformation sweeping through industrial manufacturing as companies race to integrate advanced technologies while managing persistent economic pressures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Houston Public Media, the Michigan-based company expects the restructuring to generate approximately $1 billion in annual cost savings once fully implemented. The initiative marks one of the most significant workforce reductions in Dow&amp;rsquo;s recent history and signals a broader industry shift toward technology-enabled operations that promise greater efficiency but raise questions about the future of traditional manufacturing employment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>-Zelensky's Uzbekistan-U.S. Security Agreement Stance on Armistice and Territorial Integrity - News Directory 3</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-zelensky-s-uzbekistan-u-s-security-agreement-stance-on-arm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:12:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-zelensky-s-uzbekistan-u-s-security-agreement-stance-on-arm/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sam Altman has been reinstated as CEO of OpenAI,the artificial intelligence research and deployment company,following a period of intense upheaval ⁣that saw his brief ouster and subsequent negotiations. The agreement, reached on November 22, 2023, also includes a new initial board of directors. This follows a chaotic week where Altman was first fired by the board, then courted by Microsoft, before ultimately ⁤returning to lead the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Definition / Direct Answer: Sam ⁢Altman was initially removed as CEO of OpenAI on November 17, 2023, but reinstated on November 22, 2023, after notable pressure⁢ from investors and employees.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Truth About Telus International (TIXT): Underdog Tech Stock or Total Trap?</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-truth-about-telus-international-tixt-underdog-tech-st/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:11:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-truth-about-telus-international-tixt-underdog-tech-st/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone is suddenly talking about Telus International and its TIXT stock. But is this a low-key comeback play or just another tech burnout waiting to happen? Here&amp;rsquo;s the real talk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The internet is side-eyeing Telus International right now - and for good reason. The stock has been beaten up, the AI hype cycle is peaking, and suddenly people are whispering: &amp;ldquo;Is TIXT the sleeper tech rebound?&amp;rdquo; Or is it a value trap you don&amp;rsquo;t want anywhere near your portfolio?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Great Software Reckoning: How Artificial Intelligence Is Rewriting Wall Street's Valuation Playbook</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-great-software-reckoning-how-artificial-intelligence-is/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:11:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-great-software-reckoning-how-artificial-intelligence-is/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The software industry, long regarded as one of Wall Street&amp;rsquo;s most reliable growth engines, finds itself in the midst of an existential crisis. Traditional software stocks have experienced a dramatic selloff in recent months, with investors increasingly questioning whether artificial intelligence represents an evolutionary opportunity or an extinction-level threat to established business models. The reckoning has sent shockwaves through portfolios that once treated enterprise software as a safe haven for growth capital.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Inside the Google AI Espionage Case: How Trade Secret Theft Exposes Silicon Valley's Vulnerability to Foreign Intelligence</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inside-the-google-ai-espionage-case-how-trade-secret-theft/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:11:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inside-the-google-ai-espionage-case-how-trade-secret-theft/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A California federal court has delivered a watershed verdict that reverberates through Silicon Valley&amp;rsquo;s technology corridors, finding a former Google engineer guilty of espionage and theft of artificial intelligence trade secrets. The case, which concluded with a conviction that could reshape how tech giants protect their most valuable intellectual property, centers on allegations that the engineer systematically transferred proprietary AI technology to benefit a foreign government, according to CNBC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The conviction marks one of the most significant prosecutions involving artificial intelligence trade secrets in U.S. history, arriving at a moment when AI development has become central to both economic competitiveness and national security. Federal prosecutors successfully argued that the defendant exploited his position within Google&amp;rsquo;s advanced AI research division to access and exfiltrate proprietary algorithms, training methodologies, and architectural designs that represented years of research investment and billions of dollars in development costs.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple's AI Brain Drain Accelerates as Tech Giant Struggles to Retain Top Talent Amid Intelligence Push</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-s-ai-brain-drain-accelerates-as-tech-giant-struggles-t/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:10:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-s-ai-brain-drain-accelerates-as-tech-giant-struggles-t/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple Inc. is hemorrhaging artificial intelligence expertise at a critical juncture in its technological evolution, with another wave of departures threatening the company&amp;rsquo;s ambitions to compete with rivals in the rapidly evolving AI sector. The latest exodus includes key researchers and a senior Siri executive, marking a troubling pattern for a company that has historically prided itself on employee retention and technological innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Bloomberg, the departures represent a continuation of talent losses that have plagued Apple&amp;rsquo;s AI divisions over the past several years. The company&amp;rsquo;s struggles to maintain its artificial intelligence workforce come at a time when competitors like Google, Microsoft, and OpenAI are aggressively recruiting top-tier talent and pushing the boundaries of what AI systems can accomplish. For Apple, which built its reputation on being first to market with revolutionary products, the talent drain raises questions about whether the iPhone maker can maintain its competitive edge in an industry increasingly defined by machine learning capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I Let Google's 'Auto Browse' AI Agent Take Over Chrome. It Didn't Quite Click</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-i-let-google-s-auto-browse-ai-agent-take-over-chrome-it-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:10:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-i-let-google-s-auto-browse-ai-agent-take-over-chrome-it-d/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sure, I felt some loss of control as the bot tapped away on my laptop screen. But also a kind of preemptive nostalgia for how the internet currently works, flaws and all, considering Google&amp;rsquo;s plans to fundamentally alter the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google released Auto Browse this week to US users who subscribe to its AI Pro and AI Ultra plans. Though it&amp;rsquo;s a limited release at first, Google&amp;rsquo;s core pitch appears to be an eventual reformation of the web &amp;ndash; if the bot successfully earns user trust. A web that&amp;rsquo;s ruled by automated browser bots and designed to cater to their needs, while clicking on the behalf of humans, could look alien compared to today&amp;rsquo;s user experience. For now, though, the bots seem too messy to be trusted.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rogo: $75 Million Series C Secured With Plans To Expand In Europe</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-rogo-75-million-series-c-secured-with-plans-to-expand-in-e/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:10:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-rogo-75-million-series-c-secured-with-plans-to-expand-in-e/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Rogo announced it has raised a $75 million in Series C financing led by Sequoia Capital, with participation from Henry Kravis and Wells Fargo, and continued support from existing backers Thrive Capital, Khosla Ventures, Tiger Global, and J.P. Morgan. The round brings Rogo&amp;rsquo;s total funding to more than $165 million and marks a new phase of growth as the company expands into deeper enterprise deployments across global financial institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alongside the financing, Rogo is opening its first international office in London, a move designed to accelerate customer expansion across Europe and support large firms pursuing new AI initiatives. The London office will be led by co-founder John Willett, who will spend the next year building partnerships with European financial institutions and supporting on-the-ground implementation and adoption.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Cross-Continental AI Partnership Revolutionizes Drug Discovery Through Machine Learning Framework</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-cross-continental-ai-partnership-revolutionizes-drug-discove/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:10:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-cross-continental-ai-partnership-revolutionizes-drug-discove/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking collaboration between researchers at The Ohio State University and the Indian Institute of Technology Madras has produced an artificial intelligence framework that promises to dramatically accelerate the identification of potential drug candidates, marking a significant advancement in pharmaceutical research methodology. The partnership, which bridges continents and combines expertise from two leading research institutions, represents a new model for international scientific cooperation in the age of machine learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to The Ohio State University, the AI-powered tool leverages advanced machine learning algorithms to analyze molecular structures and predict their potential effectiveness as therapeutic compounds. This development comes at a critical juncture when pharmaceutical companies face mounting pressure to reduce the time and cost associated with bringing new drugs to market, a process that traditionally takes over a decade and costs billions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Hidden Investment Frontier: How Mid-Tier Companies Are Reshaping the AI Robotics Revolution</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-hidden-investment-frontier-how-mid-tier-companies-are-r/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:09:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-hidden-investment-frontier-how-mid-tier-companies-are-r/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The artificial intelligence robotics sector has long been dominated by household names like Nvidia, Microsoft, and Tesla, but a fundamental shift is underway that sophisticated investors cannot afford to ignore. While mega-cap technology companies capture headlines and retail investor attention, a diverse ecosystem of specialized firms across the entire technology stack is emerging as the true engine of innovation &amp;ndash; and potentially superior returns &amp;ndash; in the AI robotics revolution.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gaming industry has embraced AI, but most game developers still think it's bad</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-gaming-industry-has-embraced-ai-but-most-game-developers-st/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 21:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-gaming-industry-has-embraced-ai-but-most-game-developers-st/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Half of game developers say generative AI is bad for the industry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gaming industry is experimenting with AI faster than ever, but it is doing so under a cloud of anxiety. A new industry-wide report reveals that while developers and studios are actively using generative AI tools in their daily work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a growing number of professionals believe the technology is ultimately doing more harm than good, particularly at a time when layoffs continue to shake the gaming industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Intuit Stock Is Down 24% Already In 2026. Time to Buy?</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-intuit-stock-is-down-24-already-in-2026-time-to-buy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:49:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-intuit-stock-is-down-24-already-in-2026-time-to-buy/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Intuit is still guiding for double-digit growth in fiscal 2026, but at a meaningfully slower rate than last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intuit (INTU 1.07%) stock has fallen sharply so far in 2026, despite reporting a solid fiscal first quarter in November and reiterating its full-year outlook for double-digit revenue and earnings growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why has Intuit taken a beating? It seems to be part of a broader market theme in which investors are rerating software stocks to lower valuations. Investors seem to be worried that, in an era of AI, their business models could be disrupted. In turn, many investors think that software companies should trade at lower valuation multiples.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tenable Tackles AI Governance, Shadow AI Risks, Data Exposure</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tenable-tackles-ai-governance-shadow-ai-risks-data-exposur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:48:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tenable-tackles-ai-governance-shadow-ai-risks-data-exposur/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;With adoption of AI tools among employees often outpacing the development of policies to manage their safe use, organizations are increasingly concerned about AI governance. Controlling the use of company data to train AI models and policing &amp;ldquo;shadow AI&amp;rdquo; are big concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response to these concerns, Tenable released Tenable One AI Exposure as part of its cloud-native Tenable One exposure management portfolio to detect, map, and govern the use of agentic and generative artificial intelligence (AI) platforms across all enterprise infrastructure, including cloud services and SaaS applications. The add-on, originally previewed last year, is designed to detect when employees use unsanctioned AI tools or engage in activities that pose a risk of data leakage. It also correlates the use of AI platforms, agents, libraries, and workflows with enterprise infrastructure, identity, and data, and is designed to enforce organization-wide policies governing AI usage.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AICA Announces Meeting Coordination AI Assistant Launch</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-aica-announces-meeting-coordination-ai-assistant-launch/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:47:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-aica-announces-meeting-coordination-ai-assistant-launch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Astana, Republic of Kazakhstan&amp;ndash;(Newsfile Corp. - January 30, 2026) - Today, AICA announced the launch of AICA, an AI executive assistant that facilitates meeting management for the founders, investors, and senior operators who work without an assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AICA&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To view an enhanced version of this graphic, please visit:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://images.newsfilecorp.com/files/8871/281304_824c6925b4246914_001full.jpg"&gt;https://images.newsfilecorp.com/files/8871/281304_824c6925b4246914_001full.jpg&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As companies grow, the delegation of decision-making responsibilities to additional senior leaders also increases, which means that more meeting management tasks need to be performed by senior leaders. Calendar conflicts, meeting rescheduling, and follow-up tasks are all detrimental to what should be spent on execution and decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Okonjo-Iweala urges Nigeria to shift from importing tech to local manufacturing</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-okonjo-iweala-urges-nigeria-to-shift-from-importing-tech-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:44:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-okonjo-iweala-urges-nigeria-to-shift-from-importing-tech-to/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Director-General of the World Trade Organisation, WTO, Dr. Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala, has urged Nigeria to move decisively beyond importing technology to manufacturing it locally, warning that sustained dependence on foreign technology weakens the country&amp;rsquo;s industrial base and constrains job creation in the digital economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at Ahmadu Bello University, ABU, Zaria, Okonjo-Iweala said the current disruption of the global order, driven by technology, geopolitics and climate pressures, presents both serious risks and unprecedented opportunities for Nigeria and Africa, if they are prepared to act strategically.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Jonathan Grant High students urged to use AI responsibly</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-jonathan-grant-high-students-urged-to-use-ai-responsibly/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:42:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-jonathan-grant-high-students-urged-to-use-ai-responsibly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Students at Jonathan Grant High School in Spanish Town, St Catherine, have been cautioned against misusing artificial intelligence (AI), with pupils being urged to take their education seriously and put in the necessary work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief AI consultant at Transcent AI Consulting, Marc Frankson, delivered the charge to students at the school&amp;rsquo;s annual Career Expo, which was held today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The guest speaker said that generative AI could negatively impact students&amp;rsquo; critical thinking skills.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Ambassador Kwatra outlines three-sutra framework for India AI Impact Summit, stresses people-first approach</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ambassador-kwatra-outlines-three-sutra-framework-for-india-a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:41:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ambassador-kwatra-outlines-three-sutra-framework-for-india-a/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Washington DC [US], January 31 (ANI): Indian Ambassador to the US Vinay Mohan Kwatra outlined India&amp;rsquo;s people-first approach to artificial intelligence, detailing the structure of the upcoming AI Impact Summit and saying it is built around three core pillars focused on people, planet and progress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking during a discussion titled &amp;lsquo;Exploring Global AI Policy Priorities Ahead of the India AI Impact Summit&amp;rsquo;, Kwatra said, &amp;lsquo;This is the first time that the summit is taking place in a Global South country.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Federal CIO outlines 'one government' blueprint for overhauling digital services | Federal News Network</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-federal-cio-outlines-one-government-blueprint-for-overhaul/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:39:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-federal-cio-outlines-one-government-blueprint-for-overhaul/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal Chief Information Officer Greg Barbaccia said his top priority is to get the federal government to &amp;ldquo;obsess over delivering tangible outcomes.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the Trump administration&amp;rsquo;s top tech leaders says overhauling how the federal government delivers benefits and services to the public requires the same mission discipline instilled in Marines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Your job is to kill people.&amp;rsquo; That is the first thing drilled into new recruits at the United States Marine Corps boot camp. It&amp;rsquo;s blunt by design &amp;ndash; not to glorify violence, but to create absolute clarity,&amp;rdquo; Federal Chief Information Officer Greg Barbaccia, an Army veteran, said in his opening remarks at an industry conference Friday.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Best AI Stock That Nobody's Talking About for 2026</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-best-ai-stock-that-nobody-s-talking-about-for-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:39:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-best-ai-stock-that-nobody-s-talking-about-for-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Investors should consider buying this networking stock before it skyrockets following impressive gains in the past year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several ways to benefit from the fast-growing demand for artificial intelligence (AI) technology. From chip designers to semiconductor foundries to power companies to software specialists, investors are spoiled for choice if they are looking to make money in AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies such as Palantir Technologies, Nvidia, Broadcom, and others have become popular among investors looking to capitalize on the AI boom. That&amp;rsquo;s not surprising, as these companies are the leaders in their respective markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Buzz about Broadcom's custom chips is testing, but not breaking Nvidia's dominance</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-buzz-about-broadcom-s-custom-chips-is-testing-but-not-break/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:38:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-buzz-about-broadcom-s-custom-chips-is-testing-but-not-break/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If money were not a factor, a Google software engineer says custom chips, like those from Broadcom , would always be his default selection to build cutting-edge artificial intelligence models. &amp;ldquo;I am a hundred percent using a custom chip of some sort if resources are not a constraint and I need to move fast and get as much training as possible,&amp;rdquo; said Gabriel Rasskin, who works on the Gemini AI team. &amp;ldquo;Every second of compute matters,&amp;rdquo; he stressed in an interview with CNBC. That mindset appears to be growing among hyperscalers as their appetite for custom chips rises, with Broadcom leading the way. Google used tensor processor units (TPUs), co-designed by Broadcom, to successfully train Gemini 3, whose November launch put the Alphabet unit back on the map as the large language model to beat. The performance of the TPUs also put Google in the conversation as an AI chip alternative to the industry-standard Nvidia GPUs, or graphics processing units. Every second of compute matters. Google Gemini software engineer Gabriel Rasskin Custom chips are designed for specific high-volume tasks, something Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s general-purpose GPUs are not built to do. Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang, however, recently dismissed custom chips as a threat to his business. &amp;ldquo;What Nvidia does is much more versatile,&amp;rdquo; he told Jim Cramer in an interview last month . &amp;ldquo;Nvidia can address markets that are much, much broader, not just chatbots.&amp;rdquo; Back in November , Nvidia said it was &amp;ldquo;delighted by Google&amp;rsquo;s success&amp;rdquo; in a post on X. But the post also said, &amp;ldquo;Nvidia is a generation ahead of the industry &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s the only platform that runs every AI model and does it everywhere computing is done.&amp;rdquo; To be sure, TPUs or any other competing custom chips &amp;ndash; also called application-specific integrated circuits (ASICs) &amp;ndash; are not going replace Nvidia. Google is also one of Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s biggest customers, relying on a massive number of GPUs to support its cloud infrastructure and offer customers computing power to train and run thei&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>POWERING ASEAN'S DIGITAL GROWTH</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-powering-asean-s-digital-growth/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:36:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-powering-asean-s-digital-growth/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;TM Global&amp;rsquo;s upgrades at Klang Valley Data Centre and Iskandar Puteri Data Centre are designed to accommodate rising artificial intelligence and cloud workloads across Asean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AS the digital economy accelerates, seamless connectivity is now the cornerstone of growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TM Global, Telekom Malaysia&amp;rsquo;s (TM) domestic and international wholesale arm, is empowering Malaysia to become the digital gateway of Asean, linking businesses across the region and around the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a resilient digital backbone&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Charles Schwab taps CIO to lead new tech, operations unit</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-charles-schwab-taps-cio-to-lead-new-tech-operations-unit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:36:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-charles-schwab-taps-cio-to-lead-new-tech-operations-unit/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AI is ushering in enormous change to the enterprise as CEOs push to realize the technology&amp;rsquo;s benefits. In some cases, companies are turning to CIOs to take on additional responsibilities and connect data and infrastructure with outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nearly two-thirds of executives said AI has reframed their roles within the organization, according to a December report from IT management vendor Atera. The newly defined CIO role at Charles Schwab is a sign of the close tie between technology and enterprise operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Future Focus 2026: Full Breakdown of the Four-Day Creator Sessions - OloriSuperGal</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-future-focus-2026-full-breakdown-of-the-four-day-creator-se/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:36:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-future-focus-2026-full-breakdown-of-the-four-day-creator-se/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The creator economy is evolving faster than ever, and creators who want to remain relevant, visible, and profitable must learn how to build sustainable brands, monetize strategically, and adapt to new digital systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly why Woof Studios&amp;rsquo; Future Focus Virtual Masterclass is such an important opportunity for creators in 2026.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scheduled to hold from 3rd to 6th February, 2026, Future Focus is a free virtual experience designed to equip content creators, creative entrepreneurs, and brand-led professionals with the knowledge and tools needed to thrive in the future of the creative industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tripura leads AI awareness drive ahead of India-AI Impact Summit 2026</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tripura-leads-ai-awareness-drive-ahead-of-india-ai-impact-su/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:35:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tripura-leads-ai-awareness-drive-ahead-of-india-ai-impact-su/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Agartala (Tripura) [India], January 31 (ANI): The Directorate of Information Technology, Government of Tripura, has taken a proactive step in promoting artificial intelligence (AI) awareness by organising a regional-level awareness workshop ahead of the India-AI Impact Summit 2026 on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The workshop was held at Pragya Bhavan, Agartala, as part of the pre-summit outreach activities aligned with India&amp;rsquo;s growing push towards AI-driven governance and digital service delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With rapid advancements in artificial intelligence opening new opportunities in governance, agriculture, healthcare, education and smart administration, India has accelerated AI adoption through initiatives such as the IndiaAI Mission under the Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology (MeitY) and the National Strategy for Artificial Intelligence released by NITI Aayog.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sotto Forté - The Martha's Vineyard Times</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-sotto-forte-the-martha-s-vineyard-times/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:34:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-sotto-forte-the-martha-s-vineyard-times/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This interview was published in Arts &amp;amp; Ideas, a publication by The Martha&amp;rsquo;s Vineyard Times, in 2024. After the tragic news of John Forté&amp;rsquo;s death at the start of the year, we wanted to republish the piece to our main website. The original piece can be read here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interviewed by John Battelle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Forté has made his home on Martha&amp;rsquo;s Vineyard for nearly a decade, but he&amp;rsquo;s been in love with the Island since his first visit back in 1998, when he came with a friend who just happened to be Ben Taylor, son of Island legends Carly Simon and James Taylor. Beyond a star turn with the Fugees and releasing four albums of his own, Forté has collaborated with a broad spectrum of musical talent, many of them household names &amp;ndash; beyond Simon and Ben Taylor, he&amp;rsquo;s worked with Herbie Hancock, DMX, and even Michael Jackson.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Nordic Blueprint for Building A.I. Infrastructure at Scale</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-nordic-blueprint-for-building-a-i-infrastructure-at-sca/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:33:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-nordic-blueprint-for-building-a-i-infrastructure-at-sca/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As hyperscalers race to build A.I. capacity, the Nordics offer a proven model for resilience, efficiency and sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rapid rise of A.I. is reshaping global infrastructure demands, pushing data centers from around the world to scale at unprecedented speed to support increasingly compute-intensive workloads. What was once a steady expansion has become a sprint, driven by generative A.I., large language models and real-time inference applications that strain existing power, cooling and connectivity systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Paris Hilton would consider running for office -- on one very pink condition</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-paris-hilton-would-consider-running-for-office-on-one-ver/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:33:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-paris-hilton-would-consider-running-for-office-on-one-ver/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hilton has been getting more and more involved with political advocacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris Hilton cares about politics. The TV personality and Millennial icon has become a prominent political advocate in recent years, recently joining Representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez as they urged Congress to pass the DEFIANCE Act, which would provide a legal path for victims of AI deepfakes. In a recent interview, Hilton shared her one condition for running for President.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hilton was a guest at &amp;ldquo;Today with Jenna &amp;amp; Sheinelle,&amp;rdquo; where she was asked about her desire to get more involved with politics and perhaps run for public office. &amp;ldquo;Every time I go out there, they all say that to me,&amp;rdquo; she said. &amp;ldquo;They say, &amp;lsquo;You get more done than our government.&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Advanced Micro Devices Stock Just Dropped | The Motley Fool</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-advanced-micro-devices-stock-just-dropped-the-motley-f/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:31:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-advanced-micro-devices-stock-just-dropped-the-motley-f/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a note out this morning, Wells Fargo analyst Aaron Rakers both identified the catalyst behind today&amp;rsquo;s AMD stock decline and also explained why he thinks today&amp;rsquo;s sell-off is a mistake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rakers blames a report from independent research and analysis company SemiAnalysis, which covers semiconductors in general and artificial intelligence in particular, for AMD&amp;rsquo;s sudden decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;rsquo;re probably aware, AMD is trying to break into the AI market that Nvidia (NVDA 1.41%) currently dominates. AMD says its &amp;ldquo;MI350 Series GPUs set a new standard for Generative AI and high performance computing (HPC) in data centers,&amp;rdquo; and its upcoming MI450 chip will be even better. But according to SemiAnalysis, AMD has hit a hiccup in developing the MI450, and that chip will be delayed.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Silicon Valley Double Agent: Jury Convicts Ex-Google Engineer In Landmark AI Espionage Case</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-silicon-valley-double-agent-jury-convicts-ex-google-enginee/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:30:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-silicon-valley-double-agent-jury-convicts-ex-google-enginee/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The high-stakes world of artificial intelligence just saw its first major criminal reckoning in a San Francisco courtroom. On Thursday, a federal jury found 38-year-old Linwei Ding, also known as Leon Ding, guilty on fourteen total counts &amp;ndash; seven for economic espionage and seven for the theft of trade secrets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This wasn&amp;rsquo;t just a simple case of a disgruntled employee taking files on his way out the door; it was a systematic, year-long effort to siphon the &amp;ldquo;brains&amp;rdquo; of Google&amp;rsquo;s supercomputing power for the benefit of the Chinese government.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>In the AI age, â€~slow and steadyâ€™ doesnâ€™t really win</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-in-the-ai-age-aeur-slow-and-steadyaeurtm-doesnaeurtmt-really-win/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:28:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-in-the-ai-age-aeur-slow-and-steadyaeurtm-doesnaeurtmt-really-win/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sign up for Semafor Technology: Whatâ€™s next in the new era of tech. Read it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every tech company right now is being judged on the delicate dance between industry transformation and business preservation. This week we got a better read on how CEOs are weighing risk against long-term ambition. Take Microsoft. For the first time ever, it posted a $50 billion quarter in cloud revenue, up $10 billion from a decade ago. But that growth wasnâ€™t good enough for Wall Street, and yesterdayâ€™s stock drop wiped out $357 billion in value, its steepest fall since 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MITO AI: $4.5 Million Pre-Seed Funding Closed For Collaborative AI Video Creation Platform</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-mito-ai-4-5-million-pre-seed-funding-closed-for-collaborat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:27:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-mito-ai-4-5-million-pre-seed-funding-closed-for-collaborat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;MITO AI, a Madrid- and San Francisco-based startup building a collaborative platform for AI-native video creation, has raised a $4.5 million pre-seed round led by Paul Murphy at Lightspeed Venture Partners. The company said the financing included participation from Kibo, Kfund, Sequoia, and A16Z scouts, LifeX, and angel investors, including unicorn founders and executives with ties to USV, Roblox, and GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company positions MITO as an AI orchestration layer for video production, combining foundational video, image, and audio models with professional editing tools within a browser-based, infinite-canvas environment. MITO said the product is designed for filmmakers, designers, and creative teams, with real-time collaboration features that enable multiple stakeholders to work together simultaneously in a &amp;ldquo;multiplayer&amp;rdquo; environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why AI Doesn't Think Like Humans -- How Its Unique Strength Drives Innovation</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-ai-doesn-t-think-like-humans-how-its-unique-strength/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:26:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-ai-doesn-t-think-like-humans-how-its-unique-strength/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence operates through statistical pattern recognition, ingesting massive datasets to predict outcomes without consciousness, emotions, or true reasoning. Unlike humans, AI cannot grasp sarcasm intuitively, contextualize moral dilemmas, or recall episodic memories, yet it processes enormous information volumes in seconds. This unique difference allows AI to excel at tasks requiring tireless computation, data consistency, and optimization at scales impossible for the human brain, from predicting protein folding to scanning millions of financial transactions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple AI Pin Explained: Is This Screenless Wearable Worth Wearing Every Day?</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-ai-pin-explained-is-this-screenless-wearable-worth-we/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:26:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-ai-pin-explained-is-this-screenless-wearable-worth-we/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Apple AI Pin is shaping up to be Apple&amp;rsquo;s boldest rethink of personal computing since the Apple Watch. Instead of another screen, it leans into voice, vision, and context, clipping discreetly to clothing for hands-free interaction. Designed as an iPhone companion rather than a replacement, the Apple AI Pin raises a practical question: does removing the screen make everyday tasks easier, or just more awkward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early details point to a wearable that listens, sees, and responds instantly without pulling a phone from your pocket. Apple AI aims to make interactions feel ambient rather than deliberate. Whether that shift improves daily life depends less on novelty and more on how naturally it fits into real routines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>RobCo: $100 Million Series C Raised To Scale Physical AI Robotics In U.S. And Europe</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-robco-100-million-series-c-raised-to-scale-physical-ai-rob/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:14:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-robco-100-million-series-c-raised-to-scale-physical-ai-rob/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;RobCo, a Munich-founded physical AI-driven robotics company, has raised $100 million in Series C funding to advance its &amp;ldquo;Physical AI&amp;rdquo; roadmap, expand enterprise deployments, and deepen its presence in the U.S. market. The company, founded in 2020, builds AI-enabled robotic systems designed to operate inside real production environments, targeting industrial use cases where autonomy and adaptability are increasingly critical.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The round was co-led by Lightspeed Venture Partners and Lingotto Innovation, an investment management company owned by Exor. Additional investors participating include Sequoia Capital, Greenfield Partners, Kindred Capital, Leitmotif, and The Friedkin Group. RobCo positioned the syndicate as a mix of venture investors with experience scaling software-led technology companies and industrial backers with long-term relationships and sector connectivity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dubbing Optimization for Streaming Dialogue and Singing in the AI Era</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dubbing-optimization-for-streaming-dialogue-and-singing-in-t/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:10:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dubbing-optimization-for-streaming-dialogue-and-singing-in-t/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Generative AI has transformed the technology, the workflow, and arguably the ethics of dubbing dialogue for TV and movies in recent years, with the costly and time-consuming traditional approach of a voice actor, director, and technical crew gathering in a studio for live audio replacement very much a thing of the past. The perception now is that generative AI can easily (and some would say dangerously) produce or replicate virtually any voice, but Dubformer&amp;rsquo;s Anton Dvorkovich and Google&amp;rsquo;s Nick Manoochehri insistthat generating the desired voice and refining it toward emotional precision and perfection remain challenging and as much art as science &amp;ndash; for dialogue and especially for singing &amp;ndash; as he explains in this conversation with DigitalGlue&amp;rsquo;s Philip Grossman and PADEM Media Group&amp;rsquo;s Allan McLennan at Streaming Media 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AWS Bets Big on Free AI Training as Tech Giants Race to Democratize Machine Learning Skills</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-aws-bets-big-on-free-ai-training-as-tech-giants-race-to-demo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:07:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-aws-bets-big-on-free-ai-training-as-tech-giants-race-to-demo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services has launched a comprehensive free training initiative aimed at addressing the growing skills gap in artificial intelligence, offering professionals and organizations a pathway to understanding generative AI without financial barriers. The AWS Generative AI Essentials course represents a strategic move by the cloud computing giant to expand its ecosystem while simultaneously addressing one of the technology industry&amp;rsquo;s most pressing challenges: the shortage of qualified AI practitioners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to TechRepublic, the new course provides foundational knowledge in generative AI technologies, covering everything from basic concepts to practical applications. The initiative comes at a critical juncture when organizations across industries are scrambling to integrate AI capabilities into their operations, yet find themselves constrained by a limited talent pool capable of implementing and managing these sophisticated systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple Loses More AI Researchers and a Siri Executive in Latest Departures</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-more-ai-researchers-and-a-siri-executive-in-late/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:06:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-more-ai-researchers-and-a-siri-executive-in-late/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The company has struggled to keep up with peers in the artificial intelligence race, and a decision to outsource some technology to Alphabet Inc.&amp;rsquo;s Google has rankled staff, contributing to an exodus of talent from its AI ranks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Inc. has lost at least four more of its artificial intelligence researchers in recent weeks in addition to a top Siri executive, with the staff headed to employers such as Meta Platforms Inc. and Google DeepMind.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI-Powered, People-Driven, Cox Automotive Showcases Industry-Leading Capabilities and an Unmatched Breadth of Technology at NADA 2026</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-powered-people-driven-cox-automotive-showcases-industry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:03:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-powered-people-driven-cox-automotive-showcases-industry/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cox Automotive will highlight new retail, wholesale, EV and logistics solutions at NADA 2026, reinforcing its role as the industry&amp;rsquo;s largest automotive services and technology provider.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backed by unmatched data and deep engineering expertise, Cox Automotive will show how integrated, human-centered AI is improving the retail and wholesale experience, improving efficiency, and delivering measurable ROI for dealers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cox Automotive &amp;ldquo;Experience More Stage&amp;rdquo; at NADA will feature Cox Automotive leaders &amp;quot; including President Steve Rowley, Chief Product Officer Marianne Johnson and Chief Strategy Officer Jonathan Smoke &amp;quot; along with special guests Yossi Levi, founder and CEO of Car Dealership Guy; Matt Maher, founder of M7 Innovations; Swami Sivasubramanian, vice president of agentic AI at AWS; and more.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple Loses Senior Siri Leader and AI Experts to Meta and Google DeepMind</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-senior-siri-leader-and-ai-experts-to-meta-and-go/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:02:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-senior-siri-leader-and-ai-experts-to-meta-and-go/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple continues to lose key talent from its artificial intelligence and Siri teams, adding pressure to an already sensitive transition period. Several researchers and a senior Siri executive have left in recent weeks, many heading to rival AI labs. The exits follow months of internal reshuffling and come as Apple prepares major AI upgrades tied to Siri.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a new report from Bloomberg, the latest departures include four artificial intelligence researchers alongside a top Siri executive. The report says these employees have moved to companies such as Meta and Google DeepMind, underscoring how competitive the market for AI talent has become.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Google's Project Genie 3 generates playable game worlds, raising questions for future of game development</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-google-s-project-genie-3-generates-playable-game-worlds-rai/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-google-s-project-genie-3-generates-playable-game-worlds-rai/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For the last few months, gamers have largely let big dev studios know that AI is non-negotiable in games. From the fears of Larian&amp;rsquo;s ongoing use, ARC Raiders&amp;rsquo; voice-acting debacle, and even Gen AI art in both Black Ops 6 and Battlefield 6, it is a bit wild. But now, Google has unleashed Project Genie 3 for US AI Pro subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tool is your standard prompt model, requiring players to enter a prompt. It will attempt to generate a 3D space to explore based on your queries. The demo on the site shows simple things, like a dog wandering around a front porch. But implementing it in a gaming setting seems to create some super interesting worlds. It&amp;rsquo;s creating video game-like levels with physics, models, graphics and other content.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI helps doctors detect more breast cancer cases in landmark trial</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-helps-doctors-detect-more-breast-cancer-cases-in-landmark/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-helps-doctors-detect-more-breast-cancer-cases-in-landmark/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence helps doctors spot more cases of breast cancer when reading routine scans, a world-first trial found on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results suggest countries should roll out programmes taking advantage of AI&amp;rsquo;s scanning power to ease the workload of short-staffed radiologists, the Swedish lead researchers said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well before the release of ChatGPT in 2022 raised global awareness about AI, scientists had been testing out the technology&amp;rsquo;s capacity to read medical scans.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Boosting your brain with a chip carries a price</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-boosting-your-brain-with-a-chip-carries-a-price/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-boosting-your-brain-with-a-chip-carries-a-price/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This column reflects the personal views of the author and does not necessarily reflect the opinion of the editorial board or Bloomberg LP and its owners. Parmy Olson is a Bloomberg Opinion columnist covering technology. A former reporter for The Wall Street Journal and Forbes, she is author of &amp;ldquo;Supremacy: AI, ChatGPT and the Race That Will Change the World.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you could safely implant a chip in your brain to enhance your intelligence, would you?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Sales tech stack ROI: What C-suite executives must fix now</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-sales-tech-stack-roi-what-c-suite-executives-must-fix-now/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-sales-tech-stack-roi-what-c-suite-executives-must-fix-now/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sales tech stack ROI: What C-suite executives must fix now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your sales organization is spending an average of $1,200 per rep annually on sales tools, yet 67% of purchased features go unused. According to Gartner, IT spending is growing 9.3% in 2025, but most C-suite teams can&amp;rsquo;t answer a simple question: What revenue did last quarter&amp;rsquo;s tech investment actually generate? Apollo.io explains what C-suite executives should understand about sales tech stack ROI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Recruiting, Retaining Skilled Talent to Challenge Supply Chain Organizations in 2026</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-recruiting-retaining-skilled-talent-to-challenge-supply-cha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 20:00:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-recruiting-retaining-skilled-talent-to-challenge-supply-cha/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recruiting and retaining skilled technology talent has emerged as the single biggest business challenge for 2026, cited by 50% of respondents, up sharply from 34% in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI continues to deliver measurable productivity and performance gains across organizations, but global economic uncertainty and geopolitical risk are reshaping technology investment, hiring, and innovation strategies for 2026, according to the annual Reveal Top Software Development Challenges Survey released by Infragistics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Reveal survey shows that AI is clearly delivering productivity gains, but today&amp;rsquo;s economic reality is raising the bar for every technology investment,&amp;rdquo; says Casey Ciniello, Reveal and Slingshot senior product manager, Infragistics. &amp;ldquo;The data signals a decisive shift from experimentation to disciplined execution, as talent shortages, tighter budgets, and global instability force tougher choices about where &amp;ndash; and how fast &amp;ndash; to scale. The organizations that win will be those that focus AI investment on clear, near-term business results.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a strong data analytics platform architecture | TechTarget</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-building-a-strong-data-analytics-platform-architecture-tec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:59:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-building-a-strong-data-analytics-platform-architecture-tec/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;AI assistance. Use AI to automate analysis, improve productivity and enhance data quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern architecture brings together structured, semi-structured and unstructured data. There are two prevailing strategies to do so:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strategy is complementary. Each repository addresses different analytical uses at different points in the pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data lakes lie at the front end of the pipelines and store raw data. They&amp;rsquo;re optimized for getting data into the analytics platform. Teams use landing zones and independent data sandboxes for ingestion and discovery. These native format data stores are open to private consumers for selective use. Analytics are generally limited to time-sensitive insights and exploratory inquiry by consumers who can work with data that is not yet standardized.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Use in Breast Cancer Screening Cuts Rate of Later Diagnosis</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-use-in-breast-cancer-screening-cuts-rate-of-later-diagnos/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:59:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-use-in-breast-cancer-screening-cuts-rate-of-later-diagnos/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The use of artificial intelligence in breast cancer screening reduces the rate of a cancer diagnosis by 12% in subsequent years and leads to a higher rate of early detection, according to the first trial of its kind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Researchers said the study was the largest to date looking at AI use in cancer screening. It involved 100,000 women in Sweden who were part of mammography screening and were randomly assigned to either AI-supported screening or to a standard reading by two radiologists between April 2021 and December 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Scale AI CEO: â€~Near infinite demandâ€™ for AI that works</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-scale-ai-ceo-aeur-near-infinite-demandaeurtm-for-ai-that-works/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:59:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-scale-ai-ceo-aeur-near-infinite-demandaeurtm-for-ai-that-works/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When people ask questions like â€œare companies getting ROI from their AI implementations,â€ theyâ€™re stuck in an old conversation â€&amp;quot; itâ€™s not the right measurement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies know they canâ€™t fall behind on automation, regardless of whether they can measure the impact. The question now is: What does it take to implement AI successfully? Is it plug and play? Does it require custom models or more fine-tuning after itâ€™s created?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;â€œThereâ€™s probably â€&amp;quot; Iâ€™m just going to pick a number â€&amp;quot; 3,000 to 5,000 people in the world, frankly, who can implement critical workflows that deliver value,â€ Scale AI CEO Jason Droege said at a recent Semafor event.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SDAIA launches national data, AI curriculum</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-sdaia-launches-national-data-ai-curriculum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:58:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-sdaia-launches-national-data-ai-curriculum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;RIYADH: The Saudi Data and Artificial Intelligence Authority has launched the National Cross-Disciplinary Curriculum for University Students in Data and AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It provides university students with practical fundamentals for understanding data and using AI tools responsibly to support learning, work and decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch took place during the International Conference on Data and AI Capacity Building, the Saudi Press Agency reported on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SDAIA organized the conference, which took place from Jan. 28-29, in academic partnership with King Saud University, knowledge partnership with the Human Capability Development Program, and strategic partnership with Elm.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Google's Project Genie Is Not for You</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-google-s-project-genie-is-not-for-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:58:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-google-s-project-genie-is-not-for-you/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google has a whole new world for people to play inâ€&amp;ldquo;but only for a minute. This week, the company released Project Genie, which the company calls its &amp;ldquo;general-purpose world model&amp;rdquo; that is capable of generating interactive environments. First unveiled to a small group of invite-only testers back in August of last year, the model, known as Genie 3, is now rolling out to Google AI Ultra subscribers in the US, so you can get your hands on it for the low, low price of $250 per month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nvidia AI Tech 'Powering China's Military' -- US Lawmakers</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-nvidia-ai-tech-powering-china-s-military-us-lawmakers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:58:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-nvidia-ai-tech-powering-china-s-military-us-lawmakers/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s products were used by DeepSeek and ended up supporting an AI model used by the PLA,&amp;rdquo; it said, referring to China&amp;rsquo;s People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;California-based Nvidia is the world&amp;rsquo;s most valuable company because its artificial intelligence chips are in such huge demand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But it has been caught in a geopolitical tussle between the United States and China as they compete in the fast-moving AI sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Nvidia spokesperson hit back at the claim, saying China &amp;ldquo;has more than enough domestic chips for all of its military applications, with millions to spare,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;it makes no sense for the Chinese military to depend on American technology.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Great Shift: Cybersecurity Predictions for 2026 and the New Era of Threat Intelligence</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-great-shift-cybersecurity-predictions-for-2026-and-the/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:57:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-great-shift-cybersecurity-predictions-for-2026-and-the/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we look back on 2025, AI and open source have fundamentally changed how software is built. Generative AI, automated pipelines, and ubiquitous open source have dramatically increased developer velocity and expanded what teams can deliver &amp;ndash; while shifting risk into the everyday decisions developers make as code is written, generated, and assembled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizations must acknowledge this shift and embrace an AI-powered SDLC, ensuring the right guardrails are embedded directly into the flow of development. Legacy &amp;ldquo;shift left&amp;rdquo; approaches haven&amp;rsquo;t kept up. Moving security checks earlier often just moves friction earlier, without integrating security into how developers actually work.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Arival's Global Operator Landscape Reveals Post-Pandemic Growth and Digital Disruption in Travel Experiences - Key Insights for 2026 - Travel And Tour World</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-arival-s-global-operator-landscape-reveals-post-pandemic-gro/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:56:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-arival-s-global-operator-landscape-reveals-post-pandemic-gro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Asia Pacific region, which had a delayed reopening following the pandemic, is showing the strongest growth, while Europe continues to enjoy solid demand. On the other hand, the U.S. market is facing uncertainty, particularly due to a decline in inbound tourism in 2025, which has caused some concern for future performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Are Online Travel Agencies (OTAs) Impacting the Sector?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the most significant shifts identified in the report is the growth of Online Travel Agencies (OTAs), which now account for 37% of all bookings for tours and activities, up from 33% in 2024. This surge reflects the ongoing importance of OTAs in the digital age and their growing dominance in the travel experiences market.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mesmerizing Ice Waves on Frozen Chinese Lake Break Internet (Video)</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-mesmerizing-ice-waves-on-frozen-chinese-lake-break-internet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:55:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-mesmerizing-ice-waves-on-frozen-chinese-lake-break-internet/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Sayram Lake is renowned for its natural beauty and cultural legends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the wild west out there on the internet, these days, with AI-generated videos leading to a lawlessness of suspended belief, misinformation, and skepticism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Valid, too. Some of these AI videos are just too real.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One video making the rounds recently has sparked the spidey senses of online denizens, making them wonder: Is it real or AI? It shows a frozen lake in China, with waves laden with shards of ice breaking on the frozen shore. And by all accounts, it is in fact, real.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rajeev Surendran Assary on using artificial intelligence to boost scientific and technological discovery</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-rajeev-surendran-assary-on-using-artificial-intelligence-to/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:55:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-rajeev-surendran-assary-on-using-artificial-intelligence-to/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;His work supports battery innovation, critical materials research and other efforts at Argonne.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI) and computing are becoming increasingly useful as assistants in the search for the next promising ingredient for advanced batteries, next-generation fuels and more. At the U.S. Department of Energy&amp;rsquo;s (DOE) Argonne National Laboratory, these tools are wielded by materials scientists who have spent decades exploring how different materials play a role in the future of energy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>India Signals Shift from AI Vision to Sovereign Execution with the launch of IAIRO</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-india-signals-shift-from-ai-vision-to-sovereign-execution-wi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:55:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-india-signals-shift-from-ai-vision-to-sovereign-execution-wi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;New Delhi [India], January 30: A decisive shift in India&amp;rsquo;s artificial intelligence journey is in the making with the formal launch of Indian AI Research Organisation (IAIRO), a pioneering institution and a national beacon dedicated to foundational and applied AI research aligned with India&amp;rsquo;s core challenges and priorities. Aimed at catalysing the shift - from strategy formulation to sovereignty and streamlined execution from prototypes and IP to global products - the launch of IAIRO comes at a pivotal moment backed by a position paper titled &amp;lsquo;Sovereign AI for India&amp;rsquo;s Strategic Autonomy&amp;rsquo; by Dr Amit Sheth, the Founding Director of IAIRO.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Guide for Robotic Pets in Dementia Care</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-guide-for-robotic-pets-in-dementia-care/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:49:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-guide-for-robotic-pets-in-dementia-care/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the incorporation of technology into healthcare has taken on transformative dimensions, especially when it comes to enhancing the quality of life for older adults suffering from conditions such as dementia. A groundbreaking study led by researchers including Fernandes, Toohey, and Lashewicz focuses on the utilization of robotic pets within continuing care settings in Canada. This innovative approach aims to address the emotional and psychological needs of elderly individuals, showcasing the potential technologies have in bridging gaps in traditional caregiving.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meta proves AI doubters wrong with $135 billion infrastructure push - Cryptopolitan</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-meta-proves-ai-doubters-wrong-with-135-billion-infrastructu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:47:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-meta-proves-ai-doubters-wrong-with-135-billion-infrastructu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Meta Platforms is pouring massive amounts of money into artificial intelligence, and the bet appears to be paying off through stronger advertising sales.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The social media giant plans to spend up to 135 billion dollars on infrastructure this year. That amount exceeds the total economic output of many smaller countries. The company spent 39 billion dollars in 2024 and 72 billion dollars in 2025 on capital expenses, mostly for data centers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Elon Musk Shares Bizarre AI Video Of Sydney Sweeney Weeks After Making Gross Comment About Her Body</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-elon-musk-shares-bizarre-ai-video-of-sydney-sweeney-weeks-af/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:46:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-elon-musk-shares-bizarre-ai-video-of-sydney-sweeney-weeks-af/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Just weeks after 54-year-old Elon Musk was called out for making a creepy, juvenile AI video about actor Sydney Sweeney&amp;rsquo;s breasts, he decided to promote the use of her likeness and voice to tout how great his X AI Grok Imagine &amp;ndash; a text-to-video feature &amp;ndash; is at making deep fakes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video, originally posted by another user, featured an AI created Sweeney on a spaceship speaking about Grok videos. The original prompt didn&amp;rsquo;t specify Sweeney by name, leading many to wonder if Musk had altered Grok&amp;rsquo;s responses again.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The AI Startup Venture Capitalists Are Secretly Funding</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-ai-startup-venture-capitalists-are-secretly-funding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:45:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-ai-startup-venture-capitalists-are-secretly-funding/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t directly invest in the market&amp;rsquo;s hottest AI start-ups, including OpenAI and Anthropic, unless you&amp;rsquo;re an accredited investor or a venture capitalist. However, you can still follow those companies, see how much funding they attract, and see if they&amp;rsquo;re headed for an IPO.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of those hot start-ups is Baseten, an AI infrastructure company that focuses on the inference layer &amp;ndash; the part of the AI stack that connects a trained AI model to user-facing applications. Its technology can help companies reduce inference costs by more than 40%.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>YouTube has a big incentive to nuke AI spam -- and it's starting to take action</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-youtube-has-a-big-incentive-to-nuke-ai-spam-and-it-s-st/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:43:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-youtube-has-a-big-incentive-to-nuke-ai-spam-and-it-s-st/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;YouTube is telling advertisers it&amp;rsquo;s the future of TV. AI spam could put that story in jeopardy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video platform recently shut down just over a dozen popular accounts that had been churning out AI content &amp;ndash; featuring characters like cats and Jesus &amp;ndash; according to an analysis from Kapwing, a video editing platform. Some of the channels were picking up millions of views before going dark.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November, Kapwing published a report that estimated 21% YouTube&amp;rsquo;s feed was AI-generated videos.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Wall Street Punished Microsoft But Rewarded Meta's $135 Billion AI Bet - Meta Platforms (NASDAQ:META), Microsoft (NASDAQ:MSFT)</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-wall-street-punished-microsoft-but-rewarded-meta-s-135/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:43:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-wall-street-punished-microsoft-but-rewarded-meta-s-135/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A Tale of Two AI Strategies and the Physical Reality Wall Street Finally Noticed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you watched the market on January 29, 2026, and felt confused, you&amp;rsquo;re not alone. Microsoft (NASDAQ:MSFT) reported earnings that beat expectations, yet lost nearly 10% of its value (a staggering $357 billion evaporation). On the same day, Meta (NASDAQ:META) announced it would nearly double its already-massive AI spending to as much as $135 billion in 2026, and the stock surged 10%, adding hundreds of billions in market cap.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>People Could Be 'Resurrected' in Robotic Bodies One Day, Futurist Believes. Now He's Taken the First Step.</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-people-could-be-resurrected-in-robotic-bodies-one-day-fut/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:41:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-people-could-be-resurrected-in-robotic-bodies-one-day-fut/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The irony is that during my lifetime I thought about digital immortality, about disrupting death as they say in the Valley &amp;hellip; And now I myself have become an experiment in this field &amp;hellip; This is 2025 and I&amp;rsquo;ve been dead for ten years.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;dead person&amp;rdquo; speaking these introspective lines is Roman Mazurenko &amp;ndash; or rather, Roman 2.0, an AI persona reconstructed from his posthumous traces. Mazurenko was a charismatic Belarusian engineer who died in a traffic accident in 2015 at age 35. Russian transhumanist Alexey Turchin is now rebuilding him as an open-source, long-memory project designed, in theory, to persist indefinitely.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>NASA's Perseverance Rover Completes First AI-Planned Drive on Mars</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-nasa-s-perseverance-rover-completes-first-ai-planned-drive-o/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-nasa-s-perseverance-rover-completes-first-ai-planned-drive-o/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The team for the six-wheeled scientist used a vision-capable AI to create a safe route over the Red Planet&amp;rsquo;s surface without the input of human route planners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance Mars rover has completed the first drives on another world that were planned by artificial intelligence. Executed on Dec. 8 and 10, and led by the agency&amp;rsquo;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California, the demonstration used generative AI to create waypoints for Perseverance, a complex decision-making task typically performed manually by the mission&amp;rsquo;s human rover planners.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trump Has an AI Plan. Businesses Should Make Theirs.</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-trump-has-an-ai-plan-businesses-should-make-theirs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:29:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-trump-has-an-ai-plan-businesses-should-make-theirs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For much of history, nations that possessed a technological advantage were often more successful economically and geopolitically. Looking forward, it appears that the development and deployment of artificial intelligence, or AI, will determine where those advantages manifest in the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Trump Administration&amp;rsquo;s AI Action Plan addresses the role of AI in this global game and creates a necessary framework for the U.S. to establish and protect its advantage. I believe it provides a solid foundation of policy, security, and incentives, but its ultimate success is incumbent on the level of engagement from the private sector and the underlying talent infrastructure required to bring vision to reality.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Developers say AI coding tools work -- and that's precisely what worries them</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-developers-say-ai-coding-tools-work-and-that-s-precisely/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:27:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-developers-say-ai-coding-tools-work-and-that-s-precisely/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Software developers have spent the past two years watching AI coding tools evolve from advanced autocomplete into something that can, in some cases, build entire applications from a text prompt. Tools like Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s Claude Code and OpenAI&amp;rsquo;s Codex can now work on software projects for hours at a time, writing code, running tests, and, with human supervision, fixing bugs. OpenAI says it now uses Codex to build Codex itself, and the company recently published technical details about how the tool works under the hood. It has caused many to wonder: Is this just more AI industry hype, or are things actually different this time?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple loses more AI researchers to Meta and Google DeepMind By Investing.com</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-more-ai-researchers-to-meta-and-google-deepmind/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:25:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-loses-more-ai-researchers-to-meta-and-google-deepmind/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Investing.com &amp;ndash; Apple Inc. has lost at least four more artificial intelligence researchers in recent weeks, Bloomberg reported Friday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The departing researchers include Yinfei Yang, who left to start a new company, while Haoxuan You and Bailin Wang joined Meta, the report said. You moved to Meta&amp;rsquo;s Superintelligence research division, and Bailin Wang is now working on Meta&amp;rsquo;s recommendations systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Access breaking news faster with institutional-grade feeds, immediate stock impact metrics, and analyst response tracking &amp;ndash; get 55% off InvestingPro.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>MARKETING NEWS The age of the dupe: why counterfeits are reshaping brand value</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-marketing-news-the-age-of-the-dupe-why-counterfeits-are-res/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:24:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-marketing-news-the-age-of-the-dupe-why-counterfeits-are-res/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Piracy, clone, dupe&amp;hellip; Counterfeiting has evolved and is no longer a clandestine act or reserved for the black market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Piracy, clone, dupe&amp;hellip; counterfeiting has evolved and is no longer a clandestine act reserved for the black market. In 2026, so-called &amp;ldquo;dupes&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; products that imitate the aesthetics or functionality of premium brands &amp;ndash; have become normalized as part of aspirational and cultural consumption, especially among Generation Z. Statista&amp;rsquo;s Consumer Trends 2026 report confirms that this trend is not only growing, but also redefining the relationship between consumers and brands, creating opportunities, risks, and uncomfortable questions about the true value of branding in an increasingly fragmented environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Perseverance Rover's First AI-Driven Mars Trek</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-perseverance-rover-s-first-ai-driven-mars-trek/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:16:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-perseverance-rover-s-first-ai-driven-mars-trek/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The team for the six-wheeled scientist used a vision-capable AI to create a safe route over the Red Planet&amp;rsquo;s surface without the input of human route planners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NASA&amp;rsquo;s Perseverance Mars rover has completed the first drives on another world that were planned by artificial intelligence. Executed on Dec. 8 and 10, and led by the agency&amp;rsquo;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory in Southern California, the demonstration used generative AI to create waypoints for Perseverance, a complex decision-making task typically performed manually by the mission&amp;rsquo;s human rover planners.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Man accused of using AI to alter real photos of children into explicit images</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-man-accused-of-using-ai-to-alter-real-photos-of-children-int/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:15:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-man-accused-of-using-ai-to-alter-real-photos-of-children-int/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;BOULDER COUNTY, Colo. &amp;ndash; A 72-year-old Boulder County man has been arrested and is accused of using AI to create sexually explicit images of children, the sheriff&amp;rsquo;s office announced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Daniel Fairchild was arrested Friday on a warrant for 23 counts of sexual exploitation of a child relating to the creation of child sexually exploitative material (CSEM) using online generative artificial intelligence (GenAI) tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s one of the first full investigations by the Boulder County Digital Forensics Lab (BCDFL) involving the use of generative AI to create contraband material. In this particular case, investigators believe photographs of real children were altered using generative AI to create nude and sexually exploitative images of them.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tesla, Meta, Microsoft, Power Metallic Mines, Lululemon: What brokers said this week</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tesla-meta-microsoft-power-metallic-mines-lululemon-wha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:15:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tesla-meta-microsoft-power-metallic-mines-lululemon-wha/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Jefferies analysts lowered their price target on Lululemon Athletica Inc (NASDAQ:LULU) stock to $185 from $200, coinciding with the outgoing CEO Calvin McDonald&amp;rsquo;s final day at the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares of Lululemon traded at about $174 on Friday, down almost 60% in the last 12 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;30 Jan 2026&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Inc (NASDAQ:AAPL, XETRA:APC) delivered a strong start to its fiscal 2026, with robust iPhone sales and record device installations driving better-than-expected revenue and profit for its first quarter, according to analysts, though rising memory costs could temper future gains.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Explore the top 10 STEM schools Tulsa families are raving about</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-explore-the-top-10-stem-schools-tulsa-families-are-raving-ab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-explore-the-top-10-stem-schools-tulsa-families-are-raving-ab/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For families interested in specialized education, STEM (science, technology, engineering and mathematics) schools may be the next step for your learner. Many schools lean into these subjects by encouraging hands-on learning, critical thinking and real-world application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With plenty of options across Tulsa, there&amp;rsquo;s a program to support every student&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether you&amp;rsquo;re raising a future engineer or the area&amp;rsquo;s next best surgeon, these schools will foster innovation and encourage advanced learning. Based on online data, community reviews, and information from sites like Niche, explore the best STEM schools in Tulsa and launch your child on a lifelong path to success.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Morgan Stanley Sees Economic Growth In 2026, But A More Vulnerable Market</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-morgan-stanley-sees-economic-growth-in-2026-but-a-more-vuln/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-morgan-stanley-sees-economic-growth-in-2026-but-a-more-vuln/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. economy is set up for another year of solid growth in 2026, according to Morgan Stanley. But it&amp;rsquo;s another story for the markets and stock pickers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking at the firm&amp;rsquo;s 2026 U.S. Markets Outlook media roundtable discussion, Morgan Stanley&amp;rsquo;s top investment leaders said regulatory relief, rising productivity, and massive capital spending tied to artificial intelligence should support economic growth. But they warned that elevated equity valuations could make the reward for risk less attractive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Valuing AI: Extreme Bubble, New Golden Era, or Both</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-valuing-ai-extreme-bubble-new-golden-era-or-both/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-valuing-ai-extreme-bubble-new-golden-era-or-both/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Membership is now required to use this feature. To learn more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View Membership Benefits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At GMO, we have always defined a bubble as a two-standard deviation divergence of the price of any asset class above its long-term real price trend. The U.S. stock market has now been in bubble territory for a prolonged period. Sooner or later, the bubble will burst and the price will return to its historic level.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Beam AI to Showcase Instant AI HVAC Takeoffs at AHR Expo 2026</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-beam-ai-to-showcase-instant-ai-hvac-takeoffs-at-ahr-expo-202/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-beam-ai-to-showcase-instant-ai-hvac-takeoffs-at-ahr-expo-202/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;LAS VEGAS, Jan. 30, 2026 /PRNewswire/ &amp;ndash; Beam AI, a leading AI takeoff and estimating software, has unveiled its breakthrough AI HVAC takeoff software at the AHR Expo. Estimators can now get a full-scope HVAC takeoff in under 10 minutes, cutting hours spent on estimating significantly. In addition, estimators can also obtain bid-ready AI + human-reviewed HVAC takeoffs and Excel-based estimates in 24-48 hours. Expo attendees can catch live software demos at Booth #SU2012 in South Hall at the Las Vegas Convention Centre.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Slow-growth Volusia candidates tackle issues at town hall</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-slow-growth-volusia-candidates-tackle-issues-at-town-hall/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:13:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-slow-growth-volusia-candidates-tackle-issues-at-town-hall/</guid><description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three Volusia County Council candidates aligned with the slow-growth movement shared similar views at a recent forum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The candidates expressed opposition to large developments, a proposed motocross facility, and potential AI data centers due to water usage concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They criticized the current council&amp;rsquo;s spending, particularly cutting arts funding while pursuing a multi-million-dollar motocross project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEW SMYRNA BEACH - Slow the Growth Volusia, a social-media group, hosted a Jan. 29 forum where the three County Council candidates who participated pretty much agreed on everything.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Irving Hawks take top prize at Brooklyn Public Library Robotics League championship * Brooklyn Paper</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-irving-hawks-take-top-prize-at-brooklyn-public-library-robot/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 19:02:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-irving-hawks-take-top-prize-at-brooklyn-public-library-robot/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Brooklyn Public Central Library held its annual BKLYN Library Robotics League championship on Jan. 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lobby of the Brooklyn Public Central Library&amp;rsquo;s Central Library at Grand Army Plaza buzzed with budding engineers as they competed in the annual BKLYN Library Robotics League championship on Jan. 25.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year&amp;rsquo;s top honors went to the team Irving Hawks of the Washington Irving Library, who claimed the coveted 2023 champion title, beating more than a dozen teams from libraries across the borough.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Two Trees Management brokers thirteen new leases signed in DUMBO totaling 26,000 s/f</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-two-trees-management-brokers-thirteen-new-leases-signed-in-d/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:52:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-two-trees-management-brokers-thirteen-new-leases-signed-in-d/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Brooklyn, NY Two Trees Management Co., a family-owned real estate development firm, completed thirteen new office leases in DUMBO, all signed in Q4 of 2025: Edit Church, Mammoth Projects, Apply Stickers, Helium AI, Asinc Systems, Biographer, Starling Architecture, View Source, Index Robotics, Neal Beckstedt Studio, MHI Studio, Peterson Rich, and Revise Robotics. Totaling 26,000 s/f, these leases bring Two Trees&amp;rsquo; annual total to over 200,000 s/f in new deals in DUMBO and over 325,000 s/f across the city, which is more than 50% of the commercial leases in the borough in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bangladesh Should Deploy Artificial Intelligence to Accelerate Environmental Sustainability Progress</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-bangladesh-should-deploy-artificial-intelligence-to-accelera/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:47:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-bangladesh-should-deploy-artificial-intelligence-to-accelera/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Current discourse predominantly focuses on the detrimental effects of artificial intelligence (AI), with relatively little attention given to its potential advantages. Today, I am introducing a topic where AI and its major fields can play a significant role in our overall lives. The world will face numerous substantial challenges in the future, one of the most pressing of which is achieving sustainability through environmental development. AI can be effectively applied to a wide range of environmental challenges, including climate change, energy management, resource optimization, and disaster management, and thus can play a significant role in achieving sustainability in the future. To achieve sustainability by ensuring a safe environment for human civilization, important branches of AI, such as machine learning, deep learning, computer vision, image processing, neural networks, pattern recognition, data science, and knowledge-based engineering, can play a very effective role in formulating short-term, medium-term, and long-term plans and taking practical initiatives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Arms Race Intensifies: How AI Systems Are Revolutionizing Cybersecurity Vulnerability Detection</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-arms-race-intensifies-how-ai-systems-are-revolutionizin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:38:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-the-arms-race-intensifies-how-ai-systems-are-revolutionizin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The cybersecurity industry stands at an inflection point as artificial intelligence systems demonstrate unprecedented capabilities in identifying and exploiting software vulnerabilities, fundamentally altering the dynamics between attackers and defenders. Recent developments suggest that AI-powered tools are not merely augmenting human capabilities but potentially surpassing them in certain critical areas of security research, raising profound questions about the future of digital defense strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Schneier on Security, machine learning models have achieved remarkable progress in automated vulnerability discovery, with some systems now capable of identifying zero-day exploits faster than traditional security teams. Bruce Schneier notes that this technological leap represents more than incremental improvement &amp;ndash; it signals a fundamental shift in how security vulnerabilities will be discovered, analyzed, and potentially weaponized in the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is This the Robot Equivalent of Walking While Chewing Gum?</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-is-this-the-robot-equivalent-of-walking-while-chewing-gum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:33:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-is-this-the-robot-equivalent-of-walking-while-chewing-gum/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Westwood Robotics is proud to announce a major update: THEMIS Gen2.5, the world&amp;rsquo;s first commercial full-size humanoid robot capable of manipulation on the move!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you mention it, the bit at the end where the robot picks up a can while walking? I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen a lot of that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ Westwood Robotics ]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year, Helix showed that a single neural network could control a humanoid&amp;rsquo;s upper body from pixels. Today, Helix 02 extends that control to the entire robot &amp;ndash; walking, manipulating, and balancing as one continuous system.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>DINE Group: Precision Tools Power Smart Machining</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dine-group-precision-tools-power-smart-machining/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:14:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-dine-group-precision-tools-power-smart-machining/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Modern manufacturing is like shifting seas, shaped by automation, reshored supply chains and the accelerating rise of smart factories. Most industrial giants steer like cargo ships: powerful, but slow to turn. DINE is a different kind of vessel. Agile, deliberate and horizon-focused, the company has spent the last six decades navigating change rather than resisting it, expanding from cutting tools to complete production ecosystems and, in 2018, into robotics. Now, DINE stands as both a manufacturer and a guide for the global transition to intelligent, connected and sustainable production.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Robotics Investment Opportunities Extend Beyond Big Tech</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-robotics-investment-opportunities-extend-beyond-big-tech/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:14:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-robotics-investment-opportunities-extend-beyond-big-tech/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The artificial intelligence and robotics investment opportunity extends far beyond the headline-grabbing tech giants, offering exposure to a diverse ecosystem of enablers and application developers that many investors overlook, according to experts at VettaFi&amp;rsquo;s Winter Symposium on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panelists during the &amp;ldquo;Hidden in Plain Sight: The AI &amp;amp; Robotics Ecosystem&amp;rdquo; session emphasized that investors can capture the full scope of AI disruption without picking individual stocks. The discussion explored how robotics and AI technologies are moving beyond software applications into physical-world implementations across multiple sectors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>3 Humanoid Robot Companies Shaping the Future of Automation</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-3-humanoid-robot-companies-shaping-the-future-of-automation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 18:03:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-3-humanoid-robot-companies-shaping-the-future-of-automation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;eWeek content and product recommendations are editorially independent. We may make money when you click on links to our partners. Learn More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Humanoid robots have officially entered their &amp;ldquo;wait&amp;hellip; this is actually happening&amp;rdquo; era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For years, they lived mostly in science fiction and splashy demo videos, the kind of tech that felt permanently five years away. But suddenly, humanoid robots are showing up in warehouses, factories, and investor pitch decks with real urgency.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Synthetic Data Tool Market to Hit $3.83 Billion by 2030 - Exclusive TBRC Analysis | Weekly Voice</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-synthetic-data-tool-market-to-hit-3-83-billion-by-2030-ex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:53:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-synthetic-data-tool-market-to-hit-3-83-billion-by-2030-ex/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Business Research Company&amp;rsquo;s Synthetic Data Tool Market to Hit $3.83 Billion by 2030 - Exclusive TBRC Analysis&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LONDON, GREATER LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM, January 31, 2026 /EINPresswire.com/ &amp;ndash; &amp;ldquo;The synthetic data tool market is rapidly gaining attention as organizations seek innovative solutions to handle data privacy and improve analytical capabilities. This sector&amp;rsquo;s growth is driven by technological advancements and increasing reliance on artificial intelligence and machine learning across various industries. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore the current market size, the key factors fueling growth, leading regional trends, and the main segments shaping this market&amp;rsquo;s future.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Inside Apple's Quiet Shift: How Anthropic's Claude Powers Cupertino's AI Infrastructure</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inside-apple-s-quiet-shift-how-anthropic-s-claude-powers-cu/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:32:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inside-apple-s-quiet-shift-how-anthropic-s-claude-powers-cu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s artificial intelligence strategy has taken a significant turn that challenges conventional assumptions about the iPhone maker&amp;rsquo;s technological independence. According to Bloomberg&amp;rsquo;s Mark Gurman, Apple has been running substantial portions of its AI operations on Anthropic&amp;rsquo;s Claude models rather than relying exclusively on its own proprietary systems, a revelation that underscores the complex realities facing even the world&amp;rsquo;s most valuable technology company as it navigates the generative AI revolution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The disclosure, first reported by 9to5Mac, represents a notable departure from Apple&amp;rsquo;s historically insular approach to core technologies. For decades, the company has prided itself on vertical integration &amp;ndash; designing its own silicon, operating systems, and increasingly, the software intelligence that powers user experiences. Yet the demands of large language models and generative AI appear to have prompted a more pragmatic approach, one that acknowledges the technical and resource advantages held by AI-focused companies like Anthropic.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Say what's on your mind, and AI can tell what kind of person you are</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-say-what-s-on-your-mind-and-ai-can-tell-what-kind-of-person/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:19:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-say-what-s-on-your-mind-and-ai-can-tell-what-kind-of-person/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you say a few words, generative AI will understand who you are &amp;ndash; maybe even better than your close family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new University of Michigan study found that widely available generative AI models (e.g., ChatGPT, Claude, LLaMa) can predict personality, key behaviors and daily emotions as or even more accurately than those closest to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What this study shows is AI can also help us understand ourselves better, providing insights into what makes us most human, our personalities,&amp;rdquo; said the study&amp;rsquo;s first author Aidan Wright, U-M professor of psychology and psychiatry. &amp;ldquo;Lots of people may find this of interest and useful. People have long been interested in understanding themselves better. Online personality questionnaires, some valid and many of dubious quality, are enormously popular.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Greater Generative AI Use Tied to More Depressive Symptoms</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-greater-generative-ai-use-tied-to-more-depressive-symptoms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:16:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-greater-generative-ai-use-tied-to-more-depressive-symptoms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;By Lori Solomon HealthDay Reporter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medically reviewed by Drugs.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FRIDAY, Jan. 30, 2026 &amp;ndash; Greater use of generative artificial intelligence (AI) is associated with modestly but statistically significantly greater depressive symptoms, according to a study published online Jan. 21 in JAMA Network Open.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roy H. Perlis, M.D., from Massachusetts General Hospital in Boston, and colleagues examined whether greater levels of generative AI use by U.S. adults was associated with greater levels of depressive symptoms. The analysis included survey responses from 20,847 participants.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Autonomous Car Insurance Aims to Halve Rates When Using Tesla's FSD - Kelley Blue Book</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-autonomous-car-insurance-aims-to-halve-rates-when-using-tesl/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:12:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-autonomous-car-insurance-aims-to-halve-rates-when-using-tesl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The company claims that using this insurance can cut costs in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although earlier generations thought we&amp;rsquo;d have flying cars by now, what&amp;rsquo;s becoming the new goal is self-driving cars. With both autonomous driving and AI on the rise, we should have suspected it&amp;rsquo;d only be a matter of time before the two combined in the insurance landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s where Lemonade, an AI-driven digital insurance company, is aiming to make a mark. The company has introduced a new car insurance concept that is designed for semi-autonomous cars.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Analyzes Speech to Uncover Personality Traits</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-analyzes-speech-to-uncover-personality-traits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:10:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-ai-analyzes-speech-to-uncover-personality-traits/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Study: Generative AI predicts personality traits based on open-ended narratives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you say a few words, generative AI will understand who you are-maybe even better than your close family and friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new University of Michigan study found that widely available generative AI models (e.g., ChatGPT, Claude, LLaMa) can predict personality, key behaviors and daily emotions as or even more accurately than those closest to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What this study shows is AI can also help us understand ourselves better, providing insights into what makes us most human, our personalities,&amp;rdquo; said the study&amp;rsquo;s first author Aidan Wright, U-M professor of psychology and psychiatry. &amp;ldquo;Lots of people may find this of interest and useful. People have long been interested in understanding themselves better. Online personality questionnaires, some valid and many of dubious quality, are enormously popular.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>36% of game studios using AI despite overwhelming backlash - The Mirror</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-36-of-game-studios-using-ai-despite-overwhelming-backlash/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 17:03:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-36-of-game-studios-using-ai-despite-overwhelming-backlash/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;More game developers are using generative AI year on year.(Image: Getty Images)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recent survey has discovered that 36% of game developers are using generative AI in some way, despite negative sentiment towards the technology increasing in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data comes from the Game Developers Conference, an annual event attended by video game developers around the world. Over 3,000 individuals working at development studios filled out the survey to map out industry trends - and the findings around AI use is striking.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Earnings call transcript: GM beats Q4 2025 EPS estimates, stock fluctuates By Investing.com</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-earnings-call-transcript-gm-beats-q4-2025-eps-estimates-st/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:59:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-earnings-call-transcript-gm-beats-q4-2025-eps-estimates-st/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;General Motors (GM) reported its fourth-quarter 2025 earnings, revealing an adjusted EPS of $2.51, surpassing the forecast of $2.24. Despite a revenue shortfall, the company&amp;rsquo;s stock saw significant fluctuations, with a pre-market rise of 6.89% before settling with a slight pre-market dip of 0.54%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Key Takeaways&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GM&amp;rsquo;s Q4 EPS of $2.51 exceeded expectations by 12.05%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revenue fell short, coming in at $45.29 billion against a forecast of $45.88 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock experienced a pre-market surge but showed volatility shortly after.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unbox Robotics to deploy Series B funds for faster global expansion, new product launches; seeks capex, R&amp;D push in Budget - CNBC TV18</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-unbox-robotics-to-deploy-series-b-funds-for-faster-global-ex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:57:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-unbox-robotics-to-deploy-series-b-funds-for-faster-global-ex/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Warehouse automation startup Unbox Robotics, which builds modular robotic sortation systems powered by swarm intelligence software, plans to use its freshly raised $28 million Series B funding to accelerate deployments in Europe and the US, while also investing in new product launches to deepen customer adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an interview to CNBC-TV18, Pramod Ghadge, Founder &amp;amp; CEO of Unbox Robotics, said the company&amp;rsquo;s growth is being driven by rising demand from retail, logistics, and e-commerce players looking to improve warehouse productivity and reduce friction in automation rollout.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>INVESTOR ALERT: Investigation of Richtech Robotics Inc. (RR) by Holzer &amp; Holzer, LLC</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-investor-alert-investigation-of-richtech-robotics-inc-rr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:53:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-investor-alert-investigation-of-richtech-robotics-inc-rr/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;ATLANTA, Jan. 30, 2026 (GLOBE NEWSWIRE) &amp;ndash; Holzer &amp;amp; Holzer, LLC is investigating whether Richtech Robotics Inc. (&amp;ldquo;Richtech&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;Company&amp;rdquo;) (NASDAQ: RR) complied with federal securities laws. On January 29, 2026, Hunterbrook Media released a report alleging that &amp;ldquo;no material partnership appears to exist&amp;rdquo; between Richtech Robotics&amp;rsquo; engineering team and Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s AI Co-Innovation Labs. Following this news, the price of the Company&amp;rsquo;s stock dropped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you purchased Richtech stock and suffered a loss on that investment, you are encouraged to contact Corey Holzer, Esq. at &lt;a href="mailto:cholzer@holzerlaw.com"&gt;cholzer@holzerlaw.com&lt;/a&gt; or Joshua Karr, Esq. at  &lt;a href="mailto:jkarr@holzerlaw.com"&gt;jkarr@holzerlaw.com&lt;/a&gt;, call our toll-free number at (888) 508-6832, or visit our website at &lt;a href="https://www.holzerlaw.com/case/richtech-robotics/"&gt;www.holzerlaw.com/case/richtech-robotics/&lt;/a&gt; to discuss your legal rights.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Autoliv (ALV) Q4 2025 Earnings Call Transcript | The Motley Fool</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-autoliv-alv-q4-2025-earnings-call-transcript-the-motley/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:49:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-autoliv-alv-q4-2025-earnings-call-transcript-the-motley/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Guidance on Q1 Profitability &amp;ndash; Mikael Bratt stated, &amp;ldquo;We expect adjusted operating margin in the first quarter to decline significantly compared to Q1 2025,&amp;rdquo; citing lower production, decreased engineering income, and higher depreciation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autoliv (ALV 5.13%) reported record quarterly and annual sales, driven by robust demand from Chinese and Indian OEMs, and achieved new highs in earnings per share and operating cash flow while returning $590 million to shareholders. Management guided for flat organic sales and margin expansion in 2026 despite global headwinds, with Q1 singled out as seasonally and operationally weak, particularly in China due to incentive expirations and inventory adjustments. The company announced strategic product innovation with the planned launch of foldable steering wheels for autonomous vehicles and expects to realize $20 million more in structural cost savings during the coming year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tesla's Robotaxi Retreat: What the Sudden Pause in Unsupervised Operations Reveals About Autonomous Vehicle Reality</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tesla-s-robotaxi-retreat-what-the-sudden-pause-in-unsupervi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:37:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-tesla-s-robotaxi-retreat-what-the-sudden-pause-in-unsupervi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Tesla&amp;rsquo;s ambitious push into autonomous transportation hit an unexpected speed bump this week when the electric vehicle manufacturer quietly paused unsupervised robotaxi operations, raising fundamental questions about the readiness of self-driving technology and the regulatory framework surrounding it. The decision, which comes amid heightened scrutiny of autonomous vehicle safety and Tesla&amp;rsquo;s Full Self-Driving capabilities, represents a significant setback for a company that has long positioned itself at the vanguard of transportation innovation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Protect copyrighted work used by generative AI, say Legal Affairs MEPs - PubAffairs Bruxelles</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-protect-copyrighted-work-used-by-generative-ai-say-legal-af/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:33:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-protect-copyrighted-work-used-by-generative-ai-say-legal-af/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Access to high quality data to train generative AI in the EU should go hand in hand with fair remuneration for the creative sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, Legal Affairs Committee MEPs adopted a series of proposals to ensure full transparency and fair remuneration of rightsholders for the use of copyrighted work by generative artificial intelligence (genAI), by 17 votes in favour, 3 against, and with 2 abstentions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remuneration for use of protected work&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Persona &amp; Shin Megami Tensei artist shutting down generative AI game to relaunch it on Switch</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-persona-shin-megami-tensei-artist-shutting-down-generative/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:33:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-persona-shin-megami-tensei-artist-shutting-down-generative/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The game from world-renowned artist of the Shin Megami Tensei and Persona series, Kazuma Kaneko, has revealed that his latest game, Tsukuyomi: The Divine Hunter, will be shutting down on April 22. However, Kaneko also announced that the game will be hitting the Nintendo Switch as a full-priced product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rogue-like deck-building game is riddled with generative artificial intelligence images, which, according to the company&amp;rsquo;s claims, are trained on the artist&amp;rsquo;s work. This is by design, as an &amp;ldquo;AI Kaneko&amp;rdquo;, which is intended to generate new cards based on what the player has done in the game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>UK government needs to urgently address creator concerns over AI, say two new studies</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-uk-government-needs-to-urgently-address-creator-concerns-ove/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:30:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-uk-government-needs-to-urgently-address-creator-concerns-ove/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;PRS and ISM have both published new studies on creator concerns around generative AI, seeking to put pressure on the UK government as ministers prepare to set out their long-awaited plans regarding AI and copyright. The government must ensure creator livelihoods &amp;ldquo;are protected&amp;rdquo;, PRS says&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just under 80% of UK music creators are concerned about AI-generated music competing with human-created music, according to a new survey by collecting society PRS For Music. Meanwhile, in a different study undertaken by ISM, 73% of musicians surveyed said they believe unregulated generative AI threatens their ability to earn a living.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Self-driving car trial comes to Kirkwall - The Orcadian Online</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-self-driving-car-trial-comes-to-kirkwall-the-orcadian-onli/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 16:20:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-self-driving-car-trial-comes-to-kirkwall-the-orcadian-onli/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Orkney residents will have a chance to trial the Auto-Pod self-driving vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orkney residents are being given the chance to try out a self-driving car, as part of a trial of autonomous vehicles in the county.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event builds on the work of the Kirkwall Autolink project, which is investigating whether a self‑driving, zero‑emission vehicle could improve connectivity between Kirkwall Harbour and Kirkwall Airport.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scheme is led by Urban Foresight and supported by Aurrigo and HITRANS.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>GDC 2026 report: 36% of devs use GenAI; 28% target Steam Deck and 8% target Linux</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-gdc-2026-report-36-of-devs-use-genai-28-target-steam-dec/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:45:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-gdc-2026-report-36-of-devs-use-genai-28-target-steam-dec/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The GDC 2026 State of the Game Industry full report is out with &amp;ldquo;over 2,300&amp;rdquo; professionals in the industry surveyed, and here&amp;rsquo;s some of the highlights from it. Not ideal for a comparison to last year&amp;rsquo;s survey, as there was a drop from 3,000 people surveyed in 2025 but still an interesting insight into the health of the industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with the rough side of things, sadly their data shows 11% of people survey were laid off in the last 24 months, and 17% were laid off in the last 12 months. 41% of those laid off were as a result of their studio being acquired, 63% because the studio closed and 13% due to mergers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>PlusAI shores up OEM partnership ahead of public offering</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-plusai-shores-up-oem-partnership-ahead-of-public-offering/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-plusai-shores-up-oem-partnership-ahead-of-public-offering/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This audio is auto-generated. Please let us know if you have feedback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PlusAI has secured a $25 million commitment from Volkswagen Group affiliate Traton Group to aid in scaling production of autonomous trucks, the company announced Jan. 26.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The autonomous trucking technology company&amp;rsquo;s arrangement with the Germany-based Traton Group expands upon an existing partnership that&amp;rsquo;s funding the commercial launch of factory-built driverless trucks in 2027.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aligning with established manufacturers is part of PlusAI&amp;rsquo;s strategy to rapidly deploy its technology globally as it moves closer toward its U.S. public offering, PlusAI&amp;rsquo;s COO and co-founder Shawn Kerrigan told Trucking Dive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Why Waymo's London Launch Matters</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-waymo-s-london-launch-matters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:39:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-why-waymo-s-london-launch-matters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome back to In the Loop, TIME&amp;rsquo;s new twice-weekly newsletter about AI. If you&amp;rsquo;re reading this in your browser, why not subscribe to have the next one delivered straight to your inbox?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to Know: Waymo crosses the pond&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday night, I went to a press event in London hosted by the Google-owned robotaxi firm Waymo, which announced it was aiming to make driverless taxis available to Londoners by the fourth quarter of 2026.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can AI help simplify put-away rule configuration in WMS?</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-can-ai-help-simplify-put-away-rule-configuration-in-wms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:36:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-can-ai-help-simplify-put-away-rule-configuration-in-wms/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Editor&amp;rsquo;s note: Sreekumar Somasundaram is a senior supply chain technical program manager at AWS. This article and its content was created prior to his current position with AWS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core capabilities of a warehouse management system (WMS) is its put-away engine. A put-away engine allows warehouses to model the business logic that determines where each product should be stored at the time it is received into the warehouse. Every WMS provides the ability to configure put-away rules, and during put-away execution, those rules are evaluated to determine the correct destination bin. When rules do not return a valid result, the system either presents an error or defaults to a fallback bin.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Lloyds Projects £100M Value From AI in 2026 - TechRepublic</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-lloyds-projects-ps100m-value-from-ai-in-2026-techrepublic/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:28:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-lloyds-projects-ps100m-value-from-ai-in-2026-techrepublic/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This update underscores how one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s largest banking groups is moving beyond experimentation with AI and into large-scale deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One bank is happy about the impact of AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lloyds Banking Group has highlighted the growing financial and operational impact of AI as part of its financial results, revealing that generative AI delivered around £50 million ($68.7 million) of value in 2025, with more than £100 million ($137.4 million) in additional value expected in 2026 as the technology is scaled further across the organization.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>More Developers Than Ever Believe Generative AI Is Hurting The Game Industry</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-more-developers-than-ever-believe-generative-ai-is-hurting-t/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:26:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-more-developers-than-ever-believe-generative-ai-is-hurting-t/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over 50% of game developers surveyed by GDC think generative AI is a threat to the video game industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new GDC survey shows that game developers&amp;rsquo; ire toward the use of generative AI in game development is going up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every year, the organization behind GDC Festival of Gaming releases the State of the Game Industry Report, featuring insights from thousands of developers around the video game industry. For the 2026 State of the Game Industry Report, 2,300 were surveyed for the latest one and were asked about a variety of topics, including generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Who Is Johny Srouji, Apple's Most Important Senior Executive - BW Businessworld</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-who-is-johny-srouji-apple-s-most-important-senior-executive/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 15:05:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-who-is-johny-srouji-apple-s-most-important-senior-executive/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Apple&amp;rsquo;s future no longer hinges on industrial design or supply-chain mastery. It hinges on silicon. At the centre of that transformation is Johny Srouji, the executive who reshaped Apple&amp;rsquo;s economics, margins, and competitive moat at the nanometre scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 29, 2026, Apple announced the acquisition of Israeli artificial intelligence startup Q.ai for an estimated $1.5-2 billion, making it the company&amp;rsquo;s largest acquisition since Beats in 2014. The announcement arrived just days after Apple reported its latest quarterly earnings, a set of numbers that once again reinforced an uncomfortable truth for the rest of the technology industry: Apple&amp;rsquo;s margins remain structurally resilient, its product economics unusually stable, and its long-term roadmap largely insulated from the turbulence affecting peers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nvidia, Mercedes Team Up to Bring Robotaxis to Major Cities | eWEEK</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-nvidia-mercedes-team-up-to-bring-robotaxis-to-major-cities/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:35:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-nvidia-mercedes-team-up-to-bring-robotaxis-to-major-cities/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;eWeek content and product recommendations are editorially independent. We may make money when you click on links to our partners. Learn More&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia and Mercedes-Benz are positioning themselves to join the growing group of self-driving operators offering robotaxi services in major cities, announcing an acceleration of plans to debut the technology in Mercedes S-Class cars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two companies will be joined by Uber, which will provide the app used to book the robotaxis. Alongside other European carmakers and parts suppliers, the three companies have begun coordinating operations and launch strategies to push self-driving adoption across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Machine Learning Predicts Infant Development in Low-Resource Areas</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-predicts-infant-development-in-low-resource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-predicts-infant-development-in-low-resource/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking stride towards enhancing early childhood development monitoring in underserved areas, a team of researchers has unveiled a pioneering machine learning model designed to predict developmental delays in infants from birth to six months. This innovative approach, detailed in a recent publication in Pediatric Research, signifies a transformative leap in pediatric healthcare, particularly in low-resource settings where traditional monitoring methods are often impractical or unavailable. By leveraging advanced computational techniques, the study represents a beacon of hope for millions of infants worldwide at risk of falling behind essential developmental milestones.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Self-driving taxi in London films itself running red light</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-self-driving-taxi-in-london-films-itself-running-red-light/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:32:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-self-driving-taxi-in-london-films-itself-running-red-light/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Add Yahoo as a preferred source to see more of our stories on Google.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of London&amp;rsquo;s first self-driving taxis filmed itself running a red light as it carried its company&amp;rsquo;s co-founder to Buckingham Palace to be decorated for services to AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Kendall, chief executive of the British AI startup Wayve, shared dashcam footage on social media which showed that his car was operating autonomously and had ignored a red light on Parliament Square.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Self-driving cars, drones hijacked by custom road signs</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-self-driving-cars-drones-hijacked-by-custom-road-signs/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:30:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-self-driving-cars-drones-hijacked-by-custom-road-signs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Indirect prompt injection occurs when a bot takes input data and interprets it as a command. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen this problem numerous times when AI bots were fed prompts via web pages or PDFs they read. Now, academics have shown that self-driving cars and autonomous drones will follow illicit instructions that have been written onto road signs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a new class of attack on AI systems, troublemakers can carry out these environmental indirect prompt injection attacks to hijack decision-making processes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Machine learning models for predicting treatment outcomes in chronic non-specific back pain patients undergoing lumbar extension traction</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-models-for-predicting-treatment-outcomes-in/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 14:04:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-machine-learning-models-for-predicting-treatment-outcomes-in/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;We are providing an unedited version of this manuscript to give early access to its findings. Before final publication, the manuscript will undergo further editing. Please note there may be errors present which affect the content, and all legal disclaimers apply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservative treatment for chronic non-specific low back pain (CLBP) includes lumbar extension traction (LET) to re-align lumbar lordosis (LL). This study explores the use of machine learning (ML) models to predict post-treatment outcomes in patients with CLBP undergoing LET and how these predictions can support clinical decision-making. We utilized a retrospective database of 431 consecutive patients with uncomplicated CLBP. Post-treatment variables predicted included LL, NRS pain score, and Oswestry Disability Index (ODI). Input model variables included pre-treatment LL, sacral base angle (SBA), ratio of LL/SBA fit type, NRS, ODI, frequency, duration, LET compliance, and demographic variables of age and BMI. Initial variables were analyzed to predict post-treatment outcomes. Three ML models &amp;ndash; Random Forest (RF), XGBoost, and Multilayer Perceptron (MLP) &amp;ndash; were employed to handle both continuous and categorical variables, and performance was evaluated for predictive accuracy. Factors affecting outcomes were identified using Shapley Additive Explanations. Treatment was a multimodal spine rehabilitation program featuring LET applied 3-6 times per week, varied between 4 and 10 weeks, and follow-up was performed at the end of care. Improvements in LL, NRS, and ODI were - 11.5° to - 23.6°, 7.3/10 to 3.3/10, and 33.2% to 10.4%, respectively. Among the ML models, XGBoost demonstrated the highest predictive accuracy for lumbar lordotic angle (R = 0.728) and pain score (R = 0.648), while Random Forest slightly outperformed XGBoost for ODI (0.631 vs. 0.616). MLP performed poorly for ODI predictions (R = 0.201), indicating difficulty in capturing functional disability patterns. SHAP analysis identified fit type, co&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Apple buys Q.ai to help devices read our faces</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-buys-q-ai-to-help-devices-read-our-faces/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:54:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-apple-buys-q-ai-to-help-devices-read-our-faces/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;But check your assumptions: this isn&amp;rsquo;t Beats 2.0. There&amp;rsquo;s no new headphone brand to flex. Instead, Apple is paying top dollar for tech that might let your devices understand you without you ever saying a word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days we put our phones on silent so they won&amp;rsquo;t disturb us; soon the phone will put us on silent so it can understand us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Q.ai has been operating in secrecy since its founding in 2022. Its machine-learning research focuses on interpreting &amp;ldquo;silent speech&amp;rdquo;, detecting imperceptible facial micro-movements, and subtle audio cues to infer what someone means to say.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Top 7 Email Security Tools for Enterprises in 2026</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-top-7-email-security-tools-for-enterprises-in-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:46:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-top-7-email-security-tools-for-enterprises-in-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Looking to protect your organisation&amp;rsquo;s email ecosystem from evolving threats? Explore the top 7 email security tools for enterprises in 2026 that help detect phishing, block malware, and enforce compliance across inbound and outbound communications. This guide highlights essential features, deployment options, and integration capabilities to strengthen email defence and safeguard enterprise users at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides being one of the most effective modes of commercial communication, email has become the most exploited attack surface for enterprises. High-tech phishing campaigns now use AI-generated, highly contextual content, which is often indistinguishable from legitimate commercial communication. Business Email Compromise (BEC) attacks impersonate real executives, suppliers, and finance teams, while malicious content is increasingly remain hidden in links, QR codes, and cloud file shares. Industry reports indicate that over 80% of phishing emails in 2025 contained AI-generated text, significantly increasing detection challenges. BEC alone causes billions in global financial losses each year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>To Build FSD, Is Elon Musk Being Cortés And Burning His Ships?</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-to-build-fsd-is-elon-musk-being-cortes-and-burning-his-ship/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:43:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-to-build-fsd-is-elon-musk-being-cortes-and-burning-his-ship/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Is Elon Musk&amp;rsquo;s strategy, betting the future of Tesla on the success of their efforts to make a working self-driving system with a camera-only machine learning car, similar to that of the Spanish conquistador Hernán Cortés, who legend says burned his ships so that his crew could not return home, leaving them no choice but to conquer Mexico?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tesla&amp;rsquo;s plan has been very different from the strategies of companies like Alphabet/Waymo, GM/Cruise, Amazon/Zoox, Baidu Apollo and others. These teams have taken a make-it-work first approach, using whatever hardware necessary, expecting the cost of the hardware to plummet with time and scale as is generally the case for digital electronics. Tesla chose a low-cost hardware suite (cameras and a custom processor) already present in their cars with the hope that enough software effort, particularly machine learning, would make the system work safely enough with that hardware.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>6 Best Data Science &amp; ML Platforms I Reviewed in 2026</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-6-best-data-science-ml-platforms-i-reviewed-in-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:40:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-6-best-data-science-ml-platforms-i-reviewed-in-2026/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The real challenge for data teams is how to choose a data science and machine learning platform that can keep up with growing workloads, tighter deployment cycles, and enterprise-level governance. You&amp;rsquo;re not looking for theory anymore, you&amp;rsquo;re looking for proof: which ML platforms truly deliver faster experimentation, smoother collaboration, and production-grade scalability without adding friction?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it&amp;rsquo;s an urgent question. The global data science platform market is projected to reach $776.86 billion by 2032, growing at a staggering 24.7% CAGR, fueled by the surge in generative AI and predictive analytics.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hybrid SqueezeNet and ML Models Boost Alzheimer's Diagnosis</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-hybrid-squeezenet-and-ml-models-boost-alzheimer-s-diagnosis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:30:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-hybrid-squeezenet-and-ml-models-boost-alzheimer-s-diagnosis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In recent developments in the field of artificial intelligence and medical diagnostics, researchers have successfully championed the hybrid stacking of SqueezeNet features alongside machine learning (ML) models to enhance the accuracy of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease diagnosis. This innovative approach, highlighted in their study, presents a groundbreaking way to leverage advanced neural networks in processing medical imaging and clinical data for more effective diagnosis of one of the most challenging neurodegenerative disorders.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Web Review, Week 2026-05 - ervin</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-web-review-week-2026-05-ervin/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:21:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-web-review-week-2026-05-ervin/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s go for my web review for the week 2026-05.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neocities Is Blocked by Bing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: tech, web, search, microsoft, vendor-lockin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huh? What&amp;rsquo;s going on there? I don&amp;rsquo;t see why they would exclude this domain completely, it makes no sense.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://blog.neocities.org/blog/2026/01/27/bing-block"&gt;https://blog.neocities.org/blog/2026/01/27/bing-block&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Enclosure feedback loop&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tags: tech, ai, machine-learning, gpt, copilot, enclosure, vendor-lockin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interesting point. As we see the collapse of public forums due to the usage of AI chatbots, we&amp;rsquo;re in fact witnessing a large enclosure movement. And it&amp;rsquo;ll reinforce itself as the vendors are training on the chat sessions. What used to be in public will be hidden.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A Systematic Review of Machine Learning Techniques for Predicting Compressive and Flexural Strength of Mortars - Archives of Computational Methods in Engineering</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-a-systematic-review-of-machine-learning-techniques-for-predi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:06:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-a-systematic-review-of-machine-learning-techniques-for-predi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Considering these aspects, a detailed discussion of ML models and their hyperparameter configurations is presented in the following section for the most frequently employed algorithms identified in the reviewed studies &amp;ndash; namely Artificial Neural Networks (ANN), Support Vector Machines (SVM), Random Forests (RF), Adaptive Boosting (AdaBoost), and Gradient/Extreme Gradient Boosting (GB/XGBoost).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The present section provides a comprehensive discussion of the most frequently used models for predicting mortar mechanical properties, as summarized in Table 2. This selection reflects the most widely applied and validated machine learning algorithms in the literature for predicting mortar performance. While deep learning (DL) approaches have shown great potential in civil and materials engineering, particularly for image-based tasks like microstructural analysis or crack detection, their methodology differs significantly from conventional ML techniques. DL models, such as convolutional and recurrent neural networks, are designed for high-dimensional, unstructured data, relying on automatic feature extraction rather than predefined input variables. This review focuses on conventional ML methods, which are more applicable to mortar research and allow for easier comparison of performance across studies.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Abstracting Robot Manipulation Skills via Mixture-of-Experts Diffusion Policies</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-abstracting-robot-manipulation-skills-via-mixture-of-experts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-abstracting-robot-manipulation-skills-via-mixture-of-experts/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21251v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Diffusion-based policies have recently shown strong results in robot manipulation, but their extension to multi-task scenarios is hindered by the high cost of scaling model size and demonstrations. We introduce Skill Mixture-of-Experts Policy (SMP), a diffusion-based mixture-of-experts policy that learns a compact orthogonal skill basis and uses sticky routing to compose actions from a small, task-relevant subset of experts at each step. A variational training objective supports this design, and adaptive expert activation at inference yields fast sampling without oversized backbones. We validate SMP in simulation and on a real dual-arm platform with multi-task learning and transfer learning tasks, where SMP achieves higher success rates and markedly lower inference cost than large diffusion baselines. These results indicate a practical path toward scalable, transferable multi-task manipulation: learn reusable skills once, activate only what is needed, and adapt quickly when tasks change.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deep QP Safety Filter: Model-free Learning for Reachability-based Safety Filter</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-deep-qp-safety-filter-model-free-learning-for-reachability/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-deep-qp-safety-filter-model-free-learning-for-reachability/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21297v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: We introduce Deep QP Safety Filter, a fully data-driven safety layer for black-box dynamical systems. Our method learns a Quadratic-Program (QP) safety filter without model knowledge by combining Hamilton-Jacobi (HJ) reachability with model-free learning. We construct contraction-based losses for both the safety value and its derivatives, and train two neural networks accordingly. In the exact setting, the learned critic converges to the viscosity solution (and its derivative), even for non-smooth values. Across diverse dynamical systems &amp;ndash; even including a hybrid system &amp;ndash; and multiple RL tasks, Deep QP Safety Filter substantially reduces pre-convergence failures while accelerating learning toward higher returns than strong baselines, offering a principled and practical route to safe, model-free control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Disturbance-Aware Flight Control of Robotic Gliding Blimp via Moving Mass Actuation</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-disturbance-aware-flight-control-of-robotic-gliding-blimp-vi/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-disturbance-aware-flight-control-of-robotic-gliding-blimp-vi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21188v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Robotic blimps, as lighter-than-air (LTA) aerial systems, offer long endurance and inherently safe operation but remain highly susceptible to wind disturbances. Building on recent advances in moving mass actuation, this paper addresses the lack of disturbance-aware control frameworks for LTA platforms by explicitly modeling and compensating for wind-induced effects. A moving horizon estimator (MHE) infers real-time wind perturbations and provides these estimates to a model predictive controller (MPC), enabling robust trajectory and heading regulation under varying wind conditions. The proposed approach leverages a two-degree-of-freedom (2-DoF) moving-mass mechanism to generate both inertial and aerodynamic moments for attitude and heading control, thereby enhancing flight stability in disturbance-prone environments. Extensive flight experiments under headwind and crosswind conditions show that the integrated MHE-MPC framework significantly outperforms baseline PID control, demonstrating its effectiveness for disturbance-aware LTA flight.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>HPTune: Hierarchical Proactive Tuning for Collision-Free Model Predictive Control</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-hptune-hierarchical-proactive-tuning-for-collision-free-mod/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-hptune-hierarchical-proactive-tuning-for-collision-free-mod/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21346v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Parameter tuning is a powerful approach to enhance adaptability in model predictive control (MPC) motion planners. However, existing methods typically operate in a myopic fashion that only evaluates executed actions, leading to inefficient parameter updates due to the sparsity of failure events (e.g., obstacle nearness or collision). To cope with this issue, we propose to extend evaluation from executed to non-executed actions, yielding a hierarchical proactive tuning (HPTune) framework that combines both a fast-level tuning and a slow-level tuning. The fast one adopts risk indicators of predictive closing speed and predictive proximity distance, and the slow one leverages an extended evaluation loss for closed-loop backpropagation. Additionally, we integrate HPTune with the Doppler LiDAR that provides obstacle velocities apart from position-only measurements for enhanced motion predictions, thus facilitating the implementation of HPTune. Extensive experiments on high-fidelity simulator demonstrate that HPTune achieves efficient MPC tuning and outperforms various baseline schemes in complex environments. It is found that HPTune enables situation-tailored motion planning by formulating a safe, agile collision avoidance strategy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>InspecSafe-V1: A Multimodal Benchmark for Safety Assessment in Industrial Inspection Scenarios</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inspecsafe-v1-a-multimodal-benchmark-for-safety-assessment/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-inspecsafe-v1-a-multimodal-benchmark-for-safety-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21173v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: With the rapid development of industrial intelligence and unmanned inspection, reliable perception and safety assessment for AI systems in complex and dynamic industrial sites has become a key bottleneck for deploying predictive maintenance and autonomous inspection. Most public datasets remain limited by simulated data sources, single-modality sensing, or the absence of fine-grained object-level annotations, which prevents robust scene understanding and multimodal safety reasoning for industrial foundation models. To address these limitations, InspecSafe-V1 is released as the first multimodal benchmark dataset for industrial inspection safety assessment that is collected from routine operations of real inspection robots in real-world environments. InspecSafe-V1 covers five representative industrial scenarios, including tunnels, power facilities, sintering equipment, oil and gas petrochemical plants, and coal conveyor trestles. The dataset is constructed from 41 wheeled and rail-mounted inspection robots operating at 2,239 valid inspection sites, yielding 5,013 inspection instances. For each instance, pixel-level segmentation annotations are provided for key objects in visible-spectrum images. In addition, a semantic scene description and a corresponding safety level label are provided according to practical inspection tasks. Seven synchronized sensing modalities are further included, including infrared video, audio, depth point clouds, radar point clouds, gas measurements, temperature, and humidity, to support multimodal anomaly recognition, cross-modal fusion, and comprehensive safety assessment in industrial environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Meta-ROS: A Next-Generation Middleware Architecture for Adaptive and Scalable Robotic Systems</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-meta-ros-a-next-generation-middleware-architecture-for-adap/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-meta-ros-a-next-generation-middleware-architecture-for-adap/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21011v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: The field of robotics faces significant challenges related to the complexity and interoperability of existing middleware frameworks, like ROS2, which can be difficult for new developers to adopt. To address these issues, we propose Meta-ROS, a novel middleware solution designed to streamline robotics development by simplifying integration, enhancing performance, and ensuring cross-platform compatibility. Meta-ROS leverages modern communication protocols, such as Zenoh and ZeroMQ, to enable efficient and low-latency communication across diverse hardware platforms, while also supporting various data types like audio, images, and video. We evaluated Meta-ROS&amp;rsquo;s performance through comprehensive testing, comparing it with existing middleware frameworks like ROS1 and ROS2. The results demonstrated that Meta-ROS outperforms ROS2, achieving up to 30% higher throughput, significantly reducing message latency, and optimizing resource usage. Additionally, its robust hardware support and developer-centric design facilitate seamless integration and ease of use, positioning Meta-ROS as an ideal solution for modern, real-time robotics AI applications.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Multi-Robot Decentralized Collaborative SLAM in Planetary Analogue Environments: Dataset, Challenges, and Lessons Learned</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-multi-robot-decentralized-collaborative-slam-in-planetary-an/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-multi-robot-decentralized-collaborative-slam-in-planetary-an/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21063v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Decentralized collaborative simultaneous localization and mapping (C-SLAM) is essential to enable multirobot missions in unknown environments without relying on preexisting localization and communication infrastructure. This technology is anticipated to play a key role in the exploration of the Moon, Mars, and other planets. In this article, we share insights and lessons learned from C-SLAM experiments involving three robots operating on a Mars analogue terrain and communicating over an ad hoc network. We examine the impact of limited and intermittent communication on C-SLAM performance, as well as the unique localization challenges posed by planetary-like environments. Additionally, we introduce a novel dataset collected during our experiments, which includes real-time peer-to-peer inter-robot throughput and latency measurements. This dataset aims to support future research on communication-constrained, decentralized multirobot operations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quick Heuristic Validation of Edges in Dynamic Roadmap Graphs</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-quick-heuristic-validation-of-edges-in-dynamic-roadmap-graph/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-quick-heuristic-validation-of-edges-in-dynamic-roadmap-graph/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.20968v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: In this paper we tackle the problem of adjusting roadmap graphs for robot motion planning to non-static environments. We introduce the &amp;ldquo;Red-Green-Gray&amp;rdquo; paradigm, a modification of the SPITE method, capable of classifying the validity status of nodes and edges using cheap heuristic checks, allowing fast semi-lazy roadmap updates. Given a roadmap, we use simple computational geometry methods to approximate the swept volumes of robots and perform lazy collision checks, and label a subset of the edges as invalid (red), valid (green), or unknown (gray). We present preliminary experimental results comparing our method to the well-established technique of Leven and Hutchinson, and showing increased accuracy as well as the ability to correctly label edges as invalid while maintaining comparable update runtimes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Track-centric Iterative Learning for Global Trajectory Optimization in Autonomous Racing</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-track-centric-iterative-learning-for-global-trajectory-optim/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-track-centric-iterative-learning-for-global-trajectory-optim/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21027v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: This paper presents a global trajectory optimization framework for minimizing lap time in autonomous racing under uncertain vehicle dynamics. Optimizing the trajectory over the full racing horizon is computationally expensive, and tracking such a trajectory in the real world hardly assures global optimality due to uncertain dynamics. Yet, existing work mostly focuses on dynamics learning at the tracking level, without updating the trajectory itself to account for the learned dynamics. To address these challenges, we propose a track-centric approach that directly learns and optimizes the full-horizon trajectory. We first represent trajectories through a track-agnostic parametric space in light of the wavelet transform. This space is then efficiently explored using Bayesian optimization, where the lap time of each candidate is evaluated by running simulations with the learned dynamics. This optimization is embedded in an iterative learning framework, where the optimized trajectory is deployed to collect real-world data for updating the dynamics, progressively refining the trajectory over the iterations. The effectiveness of the proposed framework is validated through simulations and real-world experiments, demonstrating lap time improvement of up to 20.7% over a nominal baseline and consistently outperforming state-of-the-art methods.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>WheelArm-Sim: A Manipulation and Navigation Combined Multimodal Synthetic Data Generation Simulator for Unified Control in Assistive Robotics</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-wheelarm-sim-a-manipulation-and-navigation-combined-multimo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-30-wheelarm-sim-a-manipulation-and-navigation-combined-multimo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;arXiv:2601.21129v1 Announce Type: new
Abstract: Wheelchairs and robotic arms enhance independent living by assisting individuals with upper-body and mobility limitations in their activities of daily living (ADLs). Although recent advancements in assistive robotics have focused on Wheelchair-Mounted Robotic Arms (WMRAs) and wheelchairs separately, integrated and unified control of the combination using machine learning models remains largely underexplored. To fill this gap, we introduce the concept of WheelArm, an integrated cyber-physical system (CPS) that combines wheelchair and robotic arm controls. Data collection is the first step toward developing WheelArm models. In this paper, we present WheelArm-Sim, a simulation framework developed in Isaac Sim for synthetic data collection. We evaluate its capability by collecting a manipulation and navigation combined multimodal dataset, comprising 13 tasks, 232 trajectories, and 67,783 samples. To demonstrate the potential of the WheelArm dataset, we implement a baseline model for action prediction in the mustard-picking task. The results illustrate that data collected from WheelArm-Sim is feasible for a data-driven machine learning model for integrated control.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Project Genie: Experimenting with infinite, interactive worlds</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-29-project-genie-experimenting-with-infinite-interactive-worl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:01:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-29-project-genie-experimenting-with-infinite-interactive-worl/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google AI Ultra subscribers in the U.S. can try out Project Genie, an experimental research prototype that lets you create and explore worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/project-genie-experimenting-with-infinite-interactive-worlds/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>D4RT: Teaching AI to see the world in four dimensions</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-16-d4rt-teaching-ai-to-see-the-world-in-four-dimensions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 10:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-16-d4rt-teaching-ai-to-see-the-world-in-four-dimensions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;D4RT: Unified, efficient 4D reconstruction and tracking up to 300x faster than prior methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/d4rt-teaching-ai-to-see-the-world-in-four-dimensions/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Veo 3.1 Ingredients to Video: More consistency, creativity and control</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-13-veo-3-1-ingredients-to-video-more-consistency-creativity-a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 17:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2026-01-13-veo-3-1-ingredients-to-video-more-consistency-creativity-a/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Our latest Veo update generates lively, dynamic clips that feel natural and engaging — and supports vertical video generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/veo-3-1-ingredients-to-video-more-consistency-creativity-and-control/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Google's year in review: 8 areas with research breakthroughs in 2025</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-23-google-s-year-in-review-8-areas-with-research-breakthroughs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:01:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-23-google-s-year-in-review-8-areas-with-research-breakthroughs/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google 2025 recap: Research breakthroughs of the year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/googles-year-in-review-8-areas-with-research-breakthroughs-in-2025/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gemini 3 Flash: frontier intelligence built for speed</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-17-gemini-3-flash-frontier-intelligence-built-for-speed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 11:58:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-17-gemini-3-flash-frontier-intelligence-built-for-speed/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Gemini 3 Flash offers frontier intelligence built for speed at a fraction of the cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/gemini-3-flash-frontier-intelligence-built-for-speed/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gemma Scope 2: helping the AI safety community deepen understanding of complex language model behavior</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-16-gemma-scope-2-helping-the-ai-safety-community-deepen-unders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 10:14:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-16-gemma-scope-2-helping-the-ai-safety-community-deepen-unders/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Open interpretability tools for language models are now available across the entire Gemma 3 family with the release of Gemma Scope 2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/gemma-scope-2-helping-the-ai-safety-community-deepen-understanding-of-complex-language-model-behavior/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Improved Gemini audio models for powerful voice experiences</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-12-improved-gemini-audio-models-for-powerful-voice-experiences/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 17:50:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-12-improved-gemini-audio-models-for-powerful-voice-experiences/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/improved-gemini-audio-models-for-powerful-voice-experiences/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Deepening our partnership with the UK AI Security Institute</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-11-deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:06:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-11-deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Google DeepMind and UK AI Security Institute (AISI) strengthen collaboration on critical AI safety and security research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/deepening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-ai-security-institute/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Strengthening our partnership with the UK government to support prosperity and security in the AI era</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-10-strengthening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-government-to-supp/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 14:59:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-10-strengthening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-government-to-supp/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Deepening our partnership with the UK government to support prosperity and security in the AI era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/strengthening-our-partnership-with-the-uk-government-to-support-prosperity-and-security-in-the-ai-era/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>FACTS Benchmark Suite: Systematically evaluating the factuality of large language models</title><link>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-09-facts-benchmark-suite-systematically-evaluating-the-factual/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 11:29:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://evofutura.com/posts/2025-12-09-facts-benchmark-suite-systematically-evaluating-the-factual/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Systematically evaluating the factuality of large language models with the FACTS Benchmark Suite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://deepmind.google/blog/facts-benchmark-suite-systematically-evaluating-the-factuality-of-large-language-models/"&gt;Read the original article&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>